Is that Teacher Wang?
هل أنت الأستاذ وانغ؟
Yes.
نعم.
Did you wash up clean?
هل غسلتها جيدًا؟
Pretty clean.
غسلتها تنظيفًا ممتازًا.
My ears were stuffed full yesterday.
أذناي امتلأتا بالماء أمس.
Mine were too.
وأنا أيضًا امتلأتا.
When I woke up this morning,
هذا الصباح حين استيقظت،
I blew my nose and it was all black inside.
حين تمخطت كان كل ما في أنفي أسود.
What's wrong with my nose?
ما الذي يحدث لأنفي؟
As soon as I blew it,
أول ما تمخطت،
it was like two black cotton pads, you know?
خرج كأنه قطعتا قطن سوداوين، أتفهم؟
Perfectly round.
مستديرتان تمامًا.
Completely intact.
وكانتا كاملتين جدًا.
Two black cotton pads.
قطعتا قطن سوداوين.
Came out first.
خرجتا أولًا.
Then came the runny stuff.
ثم خرج الباقي بعدها.
Yesterday, when I cleaned my ears,
أمس وأنا أنظّف أذني...
let me tell you,
أقول لك،
I was too embarrassed to just
كنت أستحي أن
throw the cotton swab
أرمي عود القطن
into the trash can.
مباشرة في سلة المهملات.
I was afraid the staff would think I was "poisoned."
خفت أن يظن العامل أني “تسمّمت”.
But it was fun yesterday.
لكن أمس كان ممتعًا.
Yeah, yesterday was really fun.
نعم، أمس كان ممتعًا جدًا فعلًا.
Is Xiao Hu here?
هل جاء شياو هو؟
I don't know.
لا أدري.
No sign of him coming.
لا توجد أي علامة أنه سيأتي.
What's wrong with him?
ما به؟
Xiao Hu said his stomach is acting up again.
شياو هو يقول إن معدته عادت تتعب.
Darn it.
يا ساتر.
We've really become the drivers, brother.
صرنا نحن الاثنين السائقين يا أخي.
I'll sit in the front.
سأجلس في الأمام.
It's fine, you get out.
لا بأس، انزل من السيارة.
Can I drive?
هل يمكنني أن أقود؟
Can you drive?
هل تستطيع القيادة؟
Yes.
أستطيع.
Of course.
طبعًا.
Wait, move it forward a bit.
لحظة، قدّمها قليلًا للأمام.
It's already moving.
إنها تتحرك بالفعل.
Let's go.
لننطلق.
The weather feels a bit like winter.
هذا الجو فيه إحساس شتوي قليلًا.
Yeah.
نعم.
When you learned to drive,
عندما كنتم تتعلمون القيادة سابقًا،
was it like this?
هكذا؟
Did they make you drive like this?
كانوا يتركونك تقود هكذا؟
Or like this?
أم هكذا؟
Like this.
هكذا.
Hold it lower.
أمسك من أسفل أكثر.
Back then,
نحن سابقًا...
our instructor wouldn't let us do this.
مدرّسنا لم يكن يسمح لنا بهذا.
We had to do this.
كان يقول: هكذا.
Because he was afraid that if we did that,
لأنه كان يخاف هكذا،
a sharp turn would jam our fingers.
من أن يعلق إصبعك عند انعطاف مفاجئ.
I said it's not like
قلت له: ليس إلى هذا الحد.
we're making sharp turns everywhere.
لن ننعطف فجأة في كل مكان.
Driving to the rhythm of the song.
كنت أقود على إيقاع الأغنية.
These are songs I listen to while biking.
هذه أغاني كنت أسمعها وأنا أبدّل على الدراجة.
Pedaling with so much energy.
كنت أدعس بقوة رهيبة.
Now I feel like I have nowhere to use this energy.
والآن أشعر أن هذه القوة بلا مكان تُصرف فيه.
Can't let it out.
لا أستطيع إخراجها.
You want to eat the hay bales?
أشتهي أن آكل حزمة عشب!
Watching horses eat grass looked so tasty when I was young.
وأنا صغير كنت أرى الحصان يأكل العشب بشهية.
The way they chewed.
يمضغ...
Can you feel that vibe?
هل تستطيع أن تتخيل ذلك الإحساس؟
It looked so delicious.
كان لذيذًا جدًا.
Yeah.
نعم.
I really wanted to go up and chew on it.
كنت أريد فعلًا أن أذهب وأمضغ.
Actually, I secretly tried chewing it. It's no good.
في الحقيقة مضغته سرًا مرة، لا يصلح.
I've chewed it before.
أنا مضغته أيضًا.
Watching them eat it just looked so tasty.
كنت أراه يأكل بشهية هناك.
It scratches the inside of your mouth.
يخدش داخل الفم.
That sound.
وذلك الصوت...
This is making me crave it.
جعلني أشتهي بمجرد النظر.
It's really vast here.
المكان هنا واسع جدًا.
Rice.
أرزّ الحقول.
The rice we eat comes from this stuff.
الأرز الذي نأكله هو هذا.
This rice must be super delicious.
أكيد هذا الأرز لذيذ جدًا.
I'm telling you.
أقول لك،
Right?
أليس كذلك؟
This must be super tasty.
أكيد سيكون لذيذًا جدًا.
Right here.
هنا بالضبط.
Get off.
انزلوا.
Get off the car.
انزلوا من السيارة.
We are sitting...
نجلس عند
...beside the high grain piles.
جانب كومة حبوب عالية.
That textbook lesson was about rice, right?
ذلك النص الدراسي كان عن الأرز، صحيح؟
Golden rice.
الأرز الذهبي.
Isn't there a lesson like that?
أظن كان هناك نص كهذا، أليس كذلك؟
No.
لا.
We're not from the same generation.
نحن لسنا من نفس الجيل.
Do I look ugly in this hat?
هل أبدو قبيحًا بهذه القبعة؟
This hat...
هذه القبعة...
It's probably not the hat that's ugly.
القبيح على الأرجح ليس القبعة.
I...
أنا...
You just had to...
تصرّ على أن
I'll push you in here.
أدفعك إلى داخل هذا المكان.
Into the rice paddy.
إلى حقل الأرز.
Autumn has arrived.
حلّ الخريف.
It's the harvest season again.
وجاء موسم الحصاد من جديد.
Look at this black soil under our feet.
انظروا إلى هذه التربة السوداء تحت أقدامنا.
This really is black soil.
هذه فعلًا تربة سوداء.
Look over there.
انظروا هناك.
Look at that Yangge team.
انظروا إلى فرقة يانغغه.
The young ladies are so lively.
الفتيات يلوّحن بحيوية.
So festive.
يا لها من أجواء احتفالية!
Come on.
هيا.
It's a bit windy today.
الرياح اليوم قوية قليلًا.
Thank you.
شكرًا.
Great dancing!
رقصكم رائع.
So whenever autumn comes...
وعندما يأتي الخريف دائمًا،
...the local people...
فإن أهل المنطقة
...will dance the Yangge...
يحتفلون عبر رقصة يانغغه
...to celebrate the harvest.
احتفالًا بالحصاد.
Yangge is actually my specialty.
رقصة يانغغه هذه هي تخصصي أصلًا.
Show us a bit.
أرِنا مقطعًا.
Okay.
حسنًا.
Come on.
هيا.
Men from the Northeast stand in the second row.
الرجال من الشمال الشرقي يقفون في الصف الثاني.
Darn it.
يا ساتر.
Those from other provinces stand in the third row.
ومن خارج الإقليم يقفون في الصف الثالث.
Feeling proud of my hometown.
افخروا ببلدتكم.
Here we go.
ها قد بدأنا.
Alright
تمام
The eight of us are just like this today
نحن الثمانية اليوم كذا وخلاص
Brother
يا أخي
With those skills of yours
بهالحركات البسيطة اللي عندك
I almost revoked your Northeast citizenship
كنت على وشك أشطبك من “أهل الشمال الشرقي”
I was just about to transfer you over here
كنت لسه هقول ننقلك عندنا
Now whenever I see you
دلوقتي أول ما أشوفك
I picture your face from yesterday
بتجي في بالي وشّك بتاع امبارح
If you dance the Yangge showing those pearly whites again
ولو كمان تبتسم بأسنانك البيضا وترقص يانغغه
That would be hilarious
هيبقى المنظر مضحك جدًا
It's not just my teeth that are shining
اللي يلمع مش بس أسناني
But also my little lighthouse
كمان “منارتي” الصغيرة
There's a clever design too
وفيها لمسة ذكية كمان
This is the New Oreo
ده أوريو الجديد
Light Up Dreams Limited Series
سلسلة “أضيء الحلم” المحدودة
It has lots of really fun patterns
وفيه رسومات كتير مميزة ومسلّية
Let's twist open the fun and light up dreams
يلا نفتح مزاج اللعب ونضيء الحلم سوا
Have one
كُل واحدة
We've experienced the Northeast Yangge
جرّبنا يانغغه الشمال الشرقي
Next let's experience the Northeast dialect
والجاي نجرب لهجة الشمال الشرقي
So here's how it works
بعد شوية هيكون كده
Two members from each team per round
كل جولة، من كل فريق عضوين
Will go on stage to perform Yangge
يطلعوا المسرح ويقدموا عرض يانغغه
On the backs of the performers
وخلف العضوين اللي بيعرضوا
are attached
هيتلزّق لكل واحد
local Northeast dialect words
كلمة من لهجة الشمال الشرقي المحلية
The members of the other team
وأعضاء الفريق التاني
can clap their hands
يقدروا بالتصفيق
to make the opponents spin around
يتحكموا في الخصم يلفّ
to see the dialect words on their backs
عشان يشوفوا الكلمة اللي وراه
Until all are answered correctly
لحد ما يجاوبوا كله صح
Whichever team uses fewer claps
الفريق اللي يصفّق مرات أقل
that team wins
هو اللي يفوز
and gets first pick of the campsite
ويختار موقع التخييم أولًا
Brother Teng and Anyu
Shen Teng ووانغ آنيو
as the camping hosts
بصفتهم مسؤولي التخييم
can choose your camping partners
يقدروا يختاروا رفيق التخييم بتاعهم
Let's just be the four of us
خلّينا إحنا الأربعة
Okay
تمام
You guys dance first this round
الجولة دي إنتوا ارقصوا الأول
Let's go
يلا
The two of us are up
إحنا الاتنين نطلع
Watch what an Irving spin looks like
خلّينا نشوف إيه هي “لفة أوين”
Two, one
اثنين، واحد
Come on
يلا
What if I clap my hands now?
طيب لو صفّقت دلوقتي
Clap now.
دلوقتي تصفيق
You two clap now.
دلوقتي لو صفّقت، إنتوا الاتنين
Boleng Gaizi.
بولينغ غايزي (ركبة)
I saw it.
شفتها
I'm out.
أنا خارج
You're out, so block for me.
لو هتطلع، غطّيني
I'll protect.
أنا بحميك
Come on, move forward.
يلا، لقدّام
Yes, right there. Block the view.
أيوه كده، احجب خط النظر ده
Block it.
احجبه
Block Brother Teng's view.
احجب رؤية Shen Teng
Jump once for every clap.
كل تصفيقة تقفزة
Spin around.
لفّ لفة
Come on.
يلا
Spin.
لفّ
I see he isn't dizzy.
شايفه مش متلخبط
What "Zheng"?
إيه “جِد” دي؟
Yang Le Er...
سارح نص سَرَحان
Spaced out.
سارح
Yes, just like this.
أيوه، بالضبط كده دلوقتي
Now he is "Spaced out".
دلوقتي هو سارح
Brother Teng's team clapped 22 times.
فريق Shen Teng استخدم 22 تصفيقة
I...
أنا...
I see he isn't dizzy.
شايفه مش متلخبط
Now he is "Spaced out".
دلوقتي هو سارح
Brother, why did you clap so many times?
يا كبير، ليه صفّقت كل ده؟
The number of claps decides the winner.
عدد التصفيق هو اللي بيحدد الفوز والخسارة
When was that said?
إمتى اتقال كده؟
You've clapped enough for the next two seasons.
إنت صفّقت كأنك مخلّص موسمين قدّام
How can we even lose?
إزاي هنخسر كده؟
No.
لا
I wasn't clapping just now.
أنا اللي فات ماكنتش بصفّق
I'll teach you another Northeast term.
وهعلّمكم كمان كلمة من الشمال الشرقي
This is called "Puleng Shou Flap".
ده اسمه رفرفة بولينغ
I was eating popcorn just now.
أنا كنت باكل فشار
You all saw it, right?
كلكم شفتوا، صح؟
I was flapping my hands.
أنا كنت برفرف
Flapping hands to get ready to play.
برفرف إيدي استعدادًا للعب
I really didn't clap.
أنا ما صفّقتش
This is called clapping.
ده اسمه تصفيق
Right.
أيوه
This is called flapping.
وده اسمه رفرفة
That's your problem.
دي مشكلتكم
This...
ده...
Who can out-argue him?
مين يقدر يغلبه في الجدال ده؟
Grand Master of Arguing.
ملك الخناقات
Bai seriously spun over ten times.
باي جينغ تينغ لفّ بجد حوالي عشر لفّات
Did he mishear it then?
يعني هو سمع غلط ولا إيه؟
Isn't it just...
مش هو...
Brother Teng's team's clap count...
عدد تصفيق فريق Shen Teng
Is still 22 times.
لسه 22 مرة
It's your turn to jump, brother.
دورك ترقص يا أخي
Go ahead.
يلا اطلع
Spin.
لفّ بقى
We can lose this game, right?
اللعبة دي ينفع نخسر فيها، صح؟
This round, let's...
الجولة دي
Spin him to "death".
نخلّيه يلفّ لحد “يموت”
We'll just keep clapping.
نفضل نصفّق على طول
Say we can't see.
ونقول مش شايفين
Just let Brother Teng spin there.
ونسيب Shen Teng يلفّ هناك
What does this mean?
إيه معنى ده؟
Who knows English?
مين بيعرف إنجليزي؟
The numbers are here.
الأرقام هنا
It means the numbers are here.
أيوه، الأرقام هنا
The two of us spin.
إحنا الاتنين نلفّ
You two spin.
إنتوا الاتنين تلفّوا
You two.
إنتوا الاتنين
Treat this as one and stick it on me.
اعتبروا ده ورقة واحدة ولزّقوها عندي هنا
This counts as one.
ده يتحسب له واحد
Is this okay?
ينفع كده؟
Sure.
ينفع
Why wouldn't it be?
ليه ماينفعش؟
Is that Northeast dialect?
دي لهجة الشمال الشرقي أصلًا؟
Yes.
أيوه
The numbers are right here.
الأرقام محطوطة هنا
Go for it.
يلا نغامر
No.
لا
How about we don't clap either.
إيه رأيكم ما نصفّقش إحنا كمان؟
Just let him jump.
ونسيبه هو يرقص
We won't clap in a moment.
بعد شوية ما نصفّقش
We won't clap.
ما نصفّقش
Just keep letting him jump.
ونخلّيه يفضل يرقص
Just let him jump.
خلوه يرقص بس
Did you four come here to catch up on sleep?
جايين هنا تكملوا نومكم إنتوا الأربعة؟
One more look and I'll charge you.
لو بصّيتوا كمان مرة هطلب فلوس
Dazed and Confused
تائه تمامًا
You don't think you're spinning fast, do you?
مو مفكّر إنك تلف بسرعة يعني؟
Why is there nothing on Brother Bing's back?
يا أخي بينغ، ليه ما في شي وراها؟
There is.
فيه
Look closely. There is.
دقّقوا كويس، فيه
Take a look at Brother Bing.
لمّحوا أخو بينغ مرة
Ready.
استعدّوا
Keep your eyes on Brother Bing.
ركّزوا على أخو بينغ
Three.
ثلاثة
Two.
اثنان
One.
واحد
Go.
يلا
There's nothing.
ما فيه
Where are the words?
وين الكلمات؟
There's absolutely nothing.
أكيد ما فيه
There really are no words.
فعلاً ما فيه كلمات
He really has no words.
هو فعلًا ما عنده كلمات
Nothing.
ما فيه
There is.
فيه
If you can't see it, just say so.
إذا مو واضح قولوا مو واضح
There definitely is.
أكيد فيه
There really are no words.
فعلاً ما فيه كلمات
There is. It's right there in plain sight.
فيه، واضح قدّامكم
Come on.
بلا هالحكي
If there isn't, I'm a "puppy."
إذا ما فيه فأنا “جرو”
There is.
فيه
Just shout it out.
بس نادِ
Just do your filming.
إنت صوّر بس
Did you see it?
شفته؟
Didn't see it.
ما شفته
There's nothing.
ما فيه
Look again.
شوف مرة ثانية
No.
لا
None of the four saw it.
أربعتنا ما شفنا شي
How can there be anything?
وش بعد “فيه”؟
That's too funny.
مرّة يضحّك
It's not under the hat, is it?
مو تحت القبعة، صح؟
No, we aren't that shameless.
لا، مو لهالدرجة نغش
Come on.
يلا
Three, two, one.
ثلاثة اثنان واحد
What is there? Nothing.
وش فيه؟ ما فيه
There are words.
فيه حروف
It's just abstract art now.
الحين صارت “تخمينات” بس
Pure cheating, right?
غش صريح، صح؟
I saw English.
أنا شفت إنجليزي
I didn't see anything pasted.
أنا ما شفت الملصق
Isn't English words?
الإنجليزي مو حروف يعني؟
The numbers are there.
الأرقام هناك
Translate it.
ترجمها
Where are the numbers?
وين الأرقام؟
What is it?
وش هي؟
That's not Northeast dialect.
هذا مو لهجة الشمال الشرقي
This is...
هذا
Right here.
هنا
This is specially...
هذا مخصوص
This outfit is...
هالملابس أصلًا
designed for this kind of game.
مصمّمة لهالنوع من الألعاب
Ordered this outfit a week in advance.
طالبين هالملابس من قبل أسبوع
No.
لا
It's right here, how is it not?
كيف مو هنا؟
Northeast dialect.
لهجة الشمال الشرقي
Can you read it?
تقدر تقراها؟
These ones.
هذي كم
The numbers are right here.
الأرقام هنا
The old man is seriously cheating.
الرجّال ناوي يغش بجدّ
It's actually quite interesting.
طلع ممتع بصراحة
This...
هذا
is Qiqihar.
تشيتشيهار
So you see, I didn't say anything.
عشان كذا شفت؟ أنا ما قلت شي
Didn't say a thing.
ولا شي
Let's play another round.
يلا نعيد جولة
Let's do it properly.
خلّونا نلعبها بجدّ
Do it properly.
بجدّ بجدّ
Just joking with you guys.
كنت أمزح معكم
Qiqihar people's humor.
فكاهة أهل تشيتشيهار
This doesn't represent Qiqihar.
هذا ما يمثّل تشيتشيهار
Doesn't represent it.
ما يمثّل
Let's start over.
نرجع نعيدها من جديد
We definitely need two non-locals up there.
لازم يطلع اثنين من برّا
That would be interesting.
كذا تصير أحلى
Right.
صح
I'll go with Sister Daxi.
أنا وأخت داشي نروح
Okay.
تمام
Let's send two people from our side too.
وإحنا نرسل اثنين بعد
You go too, Brother Bai.
إنت كمان روح يا أخو باي
You two go.
إنتوا الاثنين
How to spin fast?
كيف نلف أسرع؟
What angle makes you spin faster?
أي زاوية تخلّينا نلف أسرع شوي؟
You just have to pull your hand back quickly.
اسحب هاليد بسرعة لورا
You think you spun fast just now, Daxi?
تحسبك لفّيت بسرعة قبل شوي يا داشي؟
How fast do you think it was?
تظنها قد إيش سريعة؟
Still teaching over there.
وإنت لسه تعلّمنا
Crystal clear.
واضح جدًا
This is so hard.
هذا صعب مرّة
Come here.
تعال هنا
*Kengchi Kacha*
يتلعثم ويطقطق
Xiao Hu's "Kengchi" is already there.
تلعثم شياو هو موجود
Just don't know if the rest is "Kacha" or not.
بس ما ندري بعدها “طقطقة” ولا لا
Kengchi Biedu
كنغتشي بييدو (تلعثم)
You guessed it right.
خمنت صح
Good
تمام
What?
إيش؟
What does that mean?
وش يعني؟
Just speaking...
يعني الكلام
Speaking with difficulty, dilly-dallying.
يتكلم بصعوبة وببطء
You guessed it right.
خمنت صح
Good
تمام
You really have good eyes.
هذا لأن نظرك قوي
You look.
شفت؟
I didn't see a single word just now.
أنا ما شفت ولا حرف قبل شوي
Okay, let me do it.
تمام، أنا أجي
Let's move back a bit.
خلّونا نرجع شوي لورا
Why are you walking so far forward?
ليش تقدّمت لهالدرجة؟
Move back.
لورا
Bai Ge, you film.
أخو باي، إنت صوّر
You film it.
صوّر إنت
You film.
صوّر
I need to focus.
لازم أركّز
Need to focus.
لازم تركّز
Blocked "dead".
حاجبها “للآخر”
This spins fast and blocks tight.
يلف بسرعة ويغطيها بإحكام
Come on.
يلا
Spin.
لفّ
Beautiful.
حلو
I saw four characters.
شفت أربع كلمات
Four characters.
أربع كلمات
Didn't see what characters they were.
وش هي؟ ما شفتها
Come on.
يلا
Doesn't look like four characters.
بس مو باين إنها أربع كلمات
You...
إنت
No...
لا
Look.
شوف
He can't even see how many characters there are.
هو حتى كم كلمة ما يقدر يشوف
No.
لا
You come look.
تعال شوف
Six characters.
ست كلمات
We can't even see the characters clearly.
نحن الاثنين ما نقدر نشوف الكلمات بوضوح
You're seeing double, aren't you?
شكلك تشوفها مزدوجة، صح؟
I'll look again.
خلّيني أشوفها مرة ثانية
Give me one more chance.
اعطوني فرصة ثانية
Da Xi
دا شي
Something something *Qiu Shui*.
إيش إيش... ماء الخريف؟
Still need to block Anyu a bit.
لازم نحجب وانغ آنيو شوي
Bai Ge can't see.
باي جينغ تينغ ما يقدر يشوف
What *Qiu*?
أي خريف؟
*Wang Chuan*...
نسي يلبس
*Qiu Ku*.
السروال الداخلي الشتوي
Forgot to wear long johns.
نسي يلبس السروال الداخلي الشتوي
Let Da Xi spin a few more times, she'll slow down.
خلّوا دا شي تلف كم لفة زيادة وبتبطّئ
Can't give them a chance to rest.
لا تعطونهم فرصة يرتاحون
Da Xi, bring out that "Xiao Ping spin" energy.
دا شي، لفّي ذاك الصغير بنفس الحماس
Bring it out for me.
طلّعوه لي
*Whoosh!*
بسرعة كذا، فجأة
Da Xi
دا شي
Good
تمام
Beautiful
رائع
Again
مرة ثانية
Let her...
خلّوها
Let her spin continuously.
خلّوها تلفّ بشكل متواصل
Da Xi
دا شي
You two looked great dancing just now
رقصتكم هالمقطع طلع حلو
There is a "Gu"
فيه طبل
"Gu" what?
طبل إيش؟
"Gu"
طبل
Guqiu
غوتشيو
Guqiu Guqiu
غوتشيو غوتشيو
How about this, give us two chances
كذا، عطونا فرصتين
You guys come a bit closer too
وإنتوا قرّبوا شوي
Five times and I'll go over
أنت خمس مرات وأنا أجي
Is that okay?
ينفع ولا لا؟
Bargaining? You're haggling here?
قاعدين تفاصلون وتكاسرون السعر هنا؟
Can't help it, it's a competition
ما باليد حيلة، هذي مسابقة
If it's a competition, there are rules
إذا مسابقة، لها قواعد
You're the last person who should say that
أنت آخر واحد يحق له يقول هالكلام
Right
صح
Why is that statement...
ليش هالجملة بالذات؟
If there are rules, there are loopholes
إذا فيه قواعد، بنلقى لها ثغرات
Four times
أربع مرات
My bottom line is five times
حدّي الأدنى خمس مرات
Give us a chance
اعطونا فرصة واحدة
Compromise a little
تنازلوا شوي
Four times
أربع مرات
Four times to here
أربع مرات، وخلاص لحد هنا
Okay
ماشي
Come on
يلا
Do it continuously
صفّقوا ورا بعض
Can she go slower?
بتقدر تبطّئ شوي
Then we'll do three in a row
إذًا إحنا نصفّق ثلاث مرات متتالية
Okay
ماشي
Good
تمام
Beautiful
رائع
Great spotting
حافظت على وضع الرأس بشكل ممتاز
She's too fast, I can't see
هي سريعة جدًا، ما نقدر نشوف
Too fast, the speed is really fast
سريعة جدًا، هالسرعة فعلًا سريعة
Can't see it at all
ما نشوف شي أبدًا
Really can't see it
فعلاً ما نشوف
Do you think you spun fast just now, Da Xi?
تظنين إنك قبل شوي لفّيتي بسرعة يا دا شي؟
How fast do you think it was?
تظن قد إيش كانت سريعة؟
Still teaching over there
لسه قاعد يعلّم هناك
A bit closer
قرّبوا أكثر
Really can't see
فعلاً ما نشوف
You stand here
أنت هنا
Right, you stand here
إيه، أنت هنا
Give us one chance
اعطنا فرصة واحدة
You spin here
لفّ هنا
If I still can't tell
إذا لسه ما قدرت أميّز
What's in it for us?
وش الفايدة لنا؟
Exactly
بالضبط
You didn't penalize with two claps
وأنت ما تعاقبت حتى بتصفيقتين
Dignity
الكرامة
We bet our dignity
راهنّا بكرامتنا
Try it
جرّبوا
I'm convinced
استسلمت
Totally convinced
خلّيتونا نستسلم من اللعب
I'll spin three times in a row for you
أنا بلفّ لكم ثلاث لفّات متتالية
Da Xi, you stand here
دا شي، خليك هنا
You stand here and spin one for them
خليك هنا ولفّي لهم لفة
You spin once right here
خليك هنا ولفّ مرة
Won't she get dizzy?
كذا ما راح يدوّخ من اللف؟
Good, come on
تمام، يلا
One, two, three, spin
واحد اثنان ثلاثة، لفّ
I was just saying "gu."
قلتُ لك: «غو»
One "gu," one "qiu."
واحد «غو» وواحد «تشيو»
How did you just catch that?
كيف طلع فيه واحد “ممسوك توا” كمان؟
You intercepted it mid-air.
انمسك وهو بالهواء!
Gugu qiuqiu.
Guqiu
I'm looking at this word,
أنا أشوف هالكلمة
and I have no idea what it means.
وما أعرف حتى معناها.
It means something is bulging.
يعني «منفوخ ومعبّي».
It has nothing to do with bulging.
ماله علاقة بـ«منفوخ ومعبّي».
Then it's...
أجل يعني...
to rummage around.
يقلّبها ويعبث فيها شوي.
Getting closer.
قربت!
Gugu qiuqiu.
Guqiu
Does it mean the same as "mess with"?
يعني مثل «يعبث يعبث»؟
Pretty much.
تقريبًا.
They're using one
هم يستخدمون
Northeast dialect word
كلمة من الشمال الشرقي
to explain another Northeast dialect word.
ليشرحوا كلمة ثانية من الشمال الشرقي.
I also have no idea
وأنا بعد ما أدري.
what on earth you guys are explaining.
إيش قاعد تشرحون بالضبط؟
Guqiu
Guqiu
just means "mess with."
يعني «يعبث».
Mess with.
يعبث
And what does "mess with" mean?
و«يعبث» يعني إيش؟
"Mess with" means to fiddle with something.
«يعبث» يعني «يشتغل فيها ويقلّبها».
Fiddle with.
يشتغل فيها ويقلّبها
"Fiddle with" also...
وحتى «يشتغل فيها»
"Fiddle with" can be explained as "rummaging."
ممكن تفسّرها بـ«يقلّبها ويحرّكها».
Let me act it out for you, okay?
أمثّلها لكم، تمام؟
Come on.
يلا.
It's like the teacher is here,
كأن الأستاذ هنا
giving a lecture.
يشرح الدرس.
The two of us are down here listening.
ونحن الاثنين تحت نسمع.
But there's a desk here that no one can see.
بس فيه طاولة هنا، وما أحد يشوفها.
Everyone else is listening attentively.
الناس تسمع الشرح تمام.
"In this lesson, we'll talk about..."
درس اليوم نتكلم عن
And I'm here...
أنا هنا...
"What are you two fiddling with?"
إيش «Guqiu» هذا؟ أنتم الاثنين!
Then what does "Tongzi" mean?
طيب و«تونغ» معناها إيش؟
Tonggu.
يعبث.
Tonggu is like this.
«يعبث» يعني كذا.
Is there anything else you don't get?
باقي شي مو فاهمه؟
Come on, ask more.
يلا، مرة ثانية.
Got it.
فهمت.
Ask another one.
اسأل مرة ثانية.
Go ahead.
اسأل.
Don't be shy, just ask.
اسأل بكل صراحة.
Does Anyu know...
وانغ آنيو يعرف
...the difference between "Mo Sa" and "ba la"?
الفرق بين «مو سا» و«بالا»؟
Mo Sa.
مو سا
This is my first time hearing this.
أول مرة أسمعها.
I can handle this.
هذي أقدر عليها.
You say it.
قل.
Mo Sa is...
«مو سا» يعني
touching around.
تلمّس كذا وتلمّس كذا.
No.
لا.
That's wrong.
مو صحيح.
Mo Sa isn't a horizontal thing.
«مو سا» مو حركة أفقية.
Mo Sa is in one direction.
«مو سا» باتجاه واحد.
Right.
صح.
Ba la is in two directions.
«بالا» باتجاهين.
Mo Sa is like this, that's Mo Sa.
«مو سا» كذا، هذا اسمه «مو سا».
Ba la is this.
و«بالا» كذا.
Northeast culture...
ثقافة الشمال الشرقي
...is broad and profound.
واسعة وعميقة.
Tulu Fanzhang.
تولو فانجانغ (فوضوي)
Means not getting it done right.
يعني ما انعملت صح.
That's not us.
نحن مو...
Done... not done...
سوّيناها... ما سوّيناها
Done all Tulu Fanzhang.
سوّيناها تولو فانجانغ (فوضوي).
It means dirty.
يعني وصخة ومبهدلة؟
No.
لا.
Three Northeasterners...
ثلاثة من الشمال الشرقي
...three...
ثلاثة
...three interpretations.
ثلاث تفسيرات.
How come Northeast studies has...
إيش، «علم الشمال الشرقي» فيه
...PhD and Master's degrees?
دكتوراه وماجستير كمان؟
Look.
شوف.
This thing was done "tulu".
هالشغلة «تولو» يعني...
It means it wasn't done well.
يعني ما انعملت كويس.
Not done right.
ما انعملت بشكل مفهوم.
Tulu Fanzhang.
تولو فانجانغ (فوضوي)
It really does mean repeatedly.
فعلاً فيها معنى التكرار واللف والدوران شوي.
Then I'm wrong.
أجل أنا غلطان.
But for us...
بس نحن
But in Shenyang, we don't say it that way.
بس في شنيانغ ما ننطقها كذا.
In Shenyang, it means not done right.
عند شنيانغ يعني «ما انعملت صح».
Asked you to do a job and you made it Tulu Fanzhang.
أعطيناك شغلة وتسوّيها تولو فانجانغ (فوضوي)!
Where we are...
عندنا إحنا...
In Dandong...
في داندونغ هي...
You did this thing all dirty.
خلّيت الشغلة تطلع مبهدلة ووصخة.
Done dirty.
تسوّيها مبهدلة.
Pretty much the same, yeah.
تقريبًا، صح.
Three Northeasterners.
ثلاثة من الشمال الشرقي
There are three...
فيه ثلاثة...
We have three provinces in the Northeast.
الشمال الشرقي عندنا فيه ثلاث مقاطعات.
Just kidding.
أمزح.
This...
هذا...
People from the same province are fighting.
حتى أهل مقاطعة وحدة قاموا يتهاوشون!
What was our score just now?
كم كانت نقاطنا قبل شوي؟
Anyu's team used it 23 times.
وانغ آنيو استخدمها 23 مرة.
Brother Teng's team used it 22 times.
وشين تنغ هنا استخدمها 22 مرة.
Congratulations to Brother Teng's team for winning.
مبروك، فريق شين تنغ فاز.
Come on, you guys...
يلا، أنتم هنا.
...high-tech style camping gear...
معدات تخييم بطابع عالي التقنية
...and primitive style.
وطابع بدائي،
Which one do you want to choose?
أي واحد تبغون تختارون؟
High-tech style.
الطابع عالي التقنية.
High-tech.
عالي التقنية.
We choose wherever there's a pot.
نختار اللي فيه قدر طبخ.
I want to join their team.
أنا بنضم لفريقهم.
So suddenly?
بهالسرعة؟
That team...
ذاك الفريق
...seems like they'll eat well.
يبدو بنأكل طيب ونشرب زين.
Alright, everyone.
تمام يا جماعة.
Now regarding our camping base...
بما إن قاعدة التخييم الآن
Since you've made your choices...
انختارت خلاص،
...let's set off...
نطلع على طول.
...and head to our camping base.
متجهين لقاعدة التخييم حقّنا.
Let's go, everyone.
يلا مشينا يا جماعة.
Let's set off.
يلا ننطلق.
There's a bonfire over there
هناك نار مخيّم.
Won't it be warm if we light that up?
لو أشعلناها ما راح ندفي؟
Okay
حسنًا.
Let's warm up by the fire
تعالوا نتدفّى شوي على النار.
Watch out for your down jacket
انتبه لسترتك المنفوخة.
Don't get too close
لا تقترب كثيرًا.
What's stewing in here?
وش اللي يطبخونه هنا؟
Nothing's stewing
ما في شي ينطبخ.
I want to sit on top
أبي أجلس فوق.
Sit
اجلس.
You'll catch fire, I'm telling you
لو اشتعلت بقول لك.
Wang Anyu
وانغ آنيو.
We swing here in the winter
بالشتا كنا نتأرجح هنا.
Hurry up and go
يلا روح بسرعة.
Have a wonderful childhood, brother
عندك طفولة جميلة يا أخي.
Two families
عائلتان من الجهتين.
I'll take you to see
خلّوني أودّيكم تشوفون.
The high-tech campsite
مخيّم عالي التقنية.
Let's go
يلا نمشي.
Where is it?
وين؟
You two, stop acting out
لا تمثّلون هناك أنتم الاثنين.
that romantic sitcom
مسلسل رومانسي يعني!
It's too cold
البرد قوي جدًا.
Why is there a machine (robot)?
ليش فيه آلة... (روبوت)؟
There are even robots
وفيه روبوتات كمان.
The high-tech campsite has
المخيّم عالي التقنية وفّر لكم
matched some companions for everyone
بعض الرفاق المناسبين.
It can even wave
حتى يلوّح بيده.
Hello
مرحبًا.
Can you shake hands?
تعرف تصافح؟
Shake hands
صافح.
You really can
طلعت فعلًا تعرف!
It's so stable
ثابت جدًا.
Front and back work
قدّام وورا ينفع.
Look
شوف.
Sideways works too
حتى من الجنب ينفع.
You're really agile
أنت مرن فعلًا.
Can you dance?
تعرف ترقص؟
Da Xi, challenge it
يا دا شي، خذها تحدّي معه.
Xuanzi
لفة!
That big spin
هذي لفة كبيرة!
That's awesome
هذا رهيب!
It can even do this
حتى هذا يعرف يسويه!
We practiced for so long
نتمرّن كل هالوقت
Can't compare to you
وما نقدر عليك.
It's so agile
كيف كذا مرن؟
Military boxing
ملاكمة عسكرية.
It actually doesn't fall
معقول ما يطيح أبدًا!
With such small feet
ورجله صغيرة لهالدرجة.
"Sun Wukong"
“سون ووكونغ”.
That robot is looking for an opponent
الروبوت يدور خصم.
You guys
أنتم!
Come on
تعالوا.
Look how neglected he feels
شوفوه كيف متجاهَل.
Come
تعال.
It hit me, Brother Teng
ضربني يا تنغ!
Call for backup
نادوا الشباب!
Hurry, call for backup
بسرعة نادوا الشباب!
You dare touch my buddy?
تجرؤ تلمس صاحبي؟
It doesn't dare move now
ما عاد أجرؤ.
Let's shake hands
يلا صافحوا بعض.
It's okay now
خلاص ما في شي.
If you hit it, it won't hurt
حتى لو ضربته ما يتألم.
Is its balance good?
توازنه زين؟
Pretty good
جيد جدًا.
Can't push it over
ما تقدر تطيّحه بالحضن.
Behave
مؤدّب.
Found its blind spot
لقينا نقطة عماه.
It's coming for me
جاني أنا!
No, I feel like this buddy
لا، أحس هالرفيق
why is it so fierce with that thing on?
إذا لبس هالشي يصير متغطرس كذا؟
It feels like
أحس
it just added a vest
بس زادوا له صديري.
Feels like a stubborn donkey
كأنه حمار عنيد.
You know?
فاهمني؟
Its balance is wicked good
توازنه خرافي.
Ba la it
بالا له.
Balance is still wicked good
وبرضه توازنه خرافي.
It actually didn't fall
معقول ما طاح!
Don't be a nuisance
ولا تسوّي نفسك ثقيل دم.
This head
هنا.
This
هذا.
Buddy
يا صاحبي.
Calm down, calm down
اهدأ، اهدأ شوي.
Somehow I see
فجأة شفنا
what Wang Anyu looks like after learning martial arts
شكل وانغ آنيو بعد ما يتعلّم فنون قتالية.
That's so true
كلامك صح جدًا.
Always gotta make an entrance
لازم يطلع بذاك الاستعراض.
You know?
تدري؟
Right
إيه.
"The Anyu"
“آنيُو”.
Everyone
يا جماعة.
These robots
هالروبوتات
are the butlers for our winning team
هي خدم فريق الفائزين.
Behind us
واللي ورانا
is the tent for tonight's winners
هي خيمة الفائز الليلة.
This campsite is nice
هذا المخيّم ممتاز.
It's so comfortable
مريح جدًا.
This is way too high-tech
هذا عالي التقنية مرة!
This is just amazing
هذا رهيب بزيادة!
The bed is comfy too
والسرير مريح.
This bed is a real bed
هذا سرير حقيقي.
Not the inflatable kind
مو منفوخ.
Watch the house for me
راقبوا البيت لي.
We're going to eat soon
بعد شوي بنروح ناكل.
No need to force the hype
ما يحتاج تمديح مبالغ فيه.
No need to clap for everything
مو لازم تصفّقون على كل كلمة.
Chengcheng
فان تشنغ تشنغ.
Time to go back to your own home. Go
يلا ارجعوا لبيتكم، روحوا.
This is their home
هذا بيتهم هم.
This isn't our home
مو بيتنا.
Going back to our own home
ارجعوا لبيتكم.
I just want to stay here
أنا بس أبي أقعد هنا.
Where is our home?
وين بيتنا؟
Our campsite is actually pretty good too
مخيّمنا بصراحة كويس بعد.
Only one person can sleep here
هنا ينام شخص واحد بس.
This room can sleep three people
هالغرفة تنام 3 أشخاص.
Why is this person being isolated?
ليش صار هذا الشخص معزول كذا؟
This place is pretty nice, right?
المكان هذا طالع حلو، صح؟
Perfect for our camping trip
مناسب لتخييمنا.
You really know how to choose
تعرف تختار فعلًا.
Just in time for you to experience
عشان تحسّ بالتجربة شوي.
The capabilities of our Xiangjie S9T
بقدرات شيانغجيه إس 9 تي.
Xiao Yi, Xiao Yi
شياو يي، شياو يي.
Turn on Cinema Mode
شغّلي وضع السينما.
This is Harmony Smart Driving's
هذا من هارموني سمارت درايفنغ تبعنا.
First station wagon
أول سيارة سفر عندهم.
Equipped with lots of Huawei's flagship black tech
ومحمّلة بكثير من تقنيات هواوي الخارقة.
You really know your stuff
لازم واحد فاهم زيّك.
The atmosphere is spot on, right?
الجو صار مضبوط، صح؟
What's cooler is you can control it from outside
والأقوى إنك تقدر تتحكم فيها من برّا السيارة.
Whatever you want to watch, I'll pick for you
وش تبغى تشوف؟ أنا أختار لك.
Everyone saw the campsite just now
قبل شوي الكل شاف موقع التخييم.
Are you willing to invite the people from the thatched hut
هل تودّون دعوة أهل كوخ القش
To have dinner in your living room?
ليتعشّوا في صالتكم؟
Don't say it, don't ask
لا تقولوا ولا تسألوا.
No need to finish asking
ما يحتاج تكمل السؤال.
Please return quickly to your thatched huts
ارجعوا بسرعة إلى أكواخ القش الخاصة بكم.
If the other team wants to stay in a nice room
والفريق اللي جنبكم إذا يبغى غرفة أحسن،
There is also a chance
عنده فرصة كمان.
To win the right to swap campsites
يفوز بحق تبديل موقعي التخييم بين الطرفين.
What?
ماذا؟
Start
ابدأوا!
If you can surpass us
إذا قدرتوا تتفوّقوا،
You are Yang
تصيرون أنتم “الغنم”.
We are Yang
نصير إحنا “الغنم”.
Yang Chaoyue
يانغ تشاويويه.
Came up with such a lame pun
طلع بنكتة بايخة كذا.
It's too cold
الجو بارد جدًا.
Let's go into the tent for this challenge
خلّونا ندخل الخيمة ونسوي التحدي.
It got cold so suddenly
بهالبرودة فجأة،
Body heat is escaping from here
الحرارة كلها تطلع من هنا.
You have to seal this up
لازم تسكّر هذا المكان.
This has some fur
هذا شوي يخوّف.
Looks a bit more impressive
شكله صار أهيب شوي.
Tuck your hair inside your clothes
دسّ شعرك داخل الملابس.
Is that useful?
يفيد؟
Definitely useful
أكيد يفيد.
That works too
حتى هذا ينفع.
This hat is making a comeback
رجعت هالقبعة للواجهة.
Brother Mink
يا أخو الفرو.
No, I bet when he went home
لا، أظنّه أكيد رجع البيت
He thought at home
وقاعد يفكّر هناك.
"These people really don't understand fashion"
هالناس ما يفهمون بالموضة أبدًا.
"I must wear it again"
لازم أعيدها مرة ثانية.
In this temperature, it really works
بهالحرارة، تفيد جدًا.
The next task is called
المهمة الجاية اسمها
Little Ma Liang with the Magic Brush
القلم السحري ما ليانغ.
Each team sends one person to draw
كل فريق يطلع واحد يرسم.
The other three guess what he is drawing
والثلاثة الباقين يخمّنون وش يرسم.
The person drawing
اللي يرسم
Rings the bell on the table to get the right to answer
يدق الجرس على الطاولة عشان ياخذ حق الإجابة.
The two teams take turns answering
الفريقان يتناوبان الإجابة.
The team with the most correct answers wins
الفريق اللي يجاوب صح أكثر يفوز.
You guys always give
أنتم دايم تعطون
Games that favor Anyu
ألعاب تفيد وانغ آنيو.
Anyu's nickname used to be "Great Painter"
وانغ آنيو كان لقبه زمان “الرسّام الكبير”.
He even got into his local art academy
حتى كاد يدخل كلية الفنون عندهم.
It was just a
هي مجرد
Just a beautiful wish
أمنية جميلة.
Just like his pro basketball career
مثل موضوع كرة السلة الاحترافية عنده.
Who will be the first little painter?
أول رسّام صغير، مين نطلع؟
Among us
إحنا كم واحد.
My drawing is okay
أنا رسمي مو بطّال.
Bing
بينغ.
I was just about to say, based on your handwriting
كنت بقول: من خطّك
The way you write
اللي يطلع بهالشكل،
You can definitely draw
أكيد يعرف يرسم.
That's not necessarily true
مو شرط.
Chengcheng should be good at drawing too
فان تشنغ تشنغ رسمه غالبًا كويس.
I really liked
أنا أحبه جدًا.
What he drew for Jin Chen yesterday
اللي رسمه أمس لـجين تشن.
Art
فنّ.
That was a makeup expert
خبيرة مكياج، ذيك.
Then Brother Bing and I will go first
طيب أنا وأخو بينغ أولًا.
Okay
تمام.
Let's go
يلا نروح.
How do we buzz in?
كيف نجاوب بسرعة؟
We can't buzz in
إحنا ما نقدر نجاوب بسرعة.
They have to ring the bell
لازم هم يدقّون الجرس.
They ring the bell
هم يدقّون الجرس.
A food item
شيء للأكل.
Okay
حسنًا.
Sliced noodles
نودلز مقطّعة بالسكين.
That's a knife at the front, right?
قدّامها سكين، صح؟
Awesome
ممتاز.
Then Donkey Burger
طيب فطيرة لحم الحمار؟
Chop
يقطع!
Donkey
حمار.
Donkey head
رأس حمار.
Sachima
شاكِيما.
Are you Huang Sir?
أنت “السيد هوانغ”؟
Come out
اطلع!
Bing Ge's "kill" riding a horse
أخو بينغ، ذاك “يقتل” راكب الحصان.
"Kill" the one riding a horse
“يقتل” اللي راكب الحصان.
Riding a horse
يركب حصان.
But the drawing is quite creative
بس رسمه فيه إبداع بصراحة.
It's us who are dumb
إحنا اللي أغبياء.
Dragon boat racing
تجديف قارب التنين.
Double rowing
تجديف ثنائي.
Man-eating plant
نبتة آكلة للبشر.
Two people
شخصين.
Waltz
فالس.
Yangge dance
يرقص يانغغه.
Errenzhuan
إرينجوان (أداء شعبي من شمال شرق الصين).
Flying wing to wing
يطيران معًا كجناحين.
Rowing
سباق قوارب.
Dragon boat
قارب التنين.
Dragon boat race
سباق قوارب التنين.
That
ذاك...
What
ماذا؟
"Titanic"
«تيتانيك».
Fan Chengcheng, pick it up, come on
فان تشنغ تشنغ، ارفعه، يلا.
Isn't this Jack and Rose?
مو هذا جاك وروز؟
Where is Jack?
وين جاك؟
Isn't he right here?
مو هو هنا؟
Where's Rose?
وروز؟
Isn't she right here?
مو هي هنا؟
Why is Rose's head so big?
ليش رأس روز كبير كذا؟
Is Rose that big?
روز كذا كبيرة؟
I thought it was a monkey holding a pole, I thought
حسبته قرد ماسك عصا، حسبت.
Art
فنّ.
"Titanic"
«تيتانيك».
How did you guess that?
كيف عرفت؟
The two of them have their arms spread like this
الاثنين كذا فاتحين أيديهم.
Trembling
يرتجفون.
Guqiu-ing
متكتّلين ومتكوّمين.
Ten thousand horses galloping
عشرة آلاف حصان تعدو.
Circle
دائرة.
This circle is
هذه الدائرة هي...
Press
اضغط.
Chengcheng presses
تشنغ تشنغ، اضغط.
Red Dust
الدنيا الصاخبة.
"Titanic"
«تيتانيك».
Sachima
شاكِيما.
Next one, quick
اللي بعده، بسرعة!
Me?
أنا؟
What the heck is this
وش هذا؟
So fast
بهذه السرعة؟
Sketch master
سيّد الرسم السريع
Jin Chen
جين تشن
Fight the Landlord
لعبة المزارع
Five characters
خمس كلمات
Happy Fight the Landlord
لعبة المزارع المرِحة
I drew yesterday's Jin Chen
أنا رسمت جين تشن أمس
In Happy Fight the Landlord
داخل لعبة المزارع المرِحة
The one that looks exactly the same
نفسه تمامًا
It really does look like her
فعلاً يشبه كثيرًا
What
ماذا؟
Why are you serving dishes so fast over there?
كيف الأكل عندكم يطلع بسرعة كذا؟
Gotta take the bell away
لازم تاخذون الجرس معكم
Prison
السجن
Iron Window Love
حبّ خلف القضبان
Cold Palace
القصر المهجور
Quick, Little Hu, quick
بسرعة يا شياو هو، بسرعة
Okay
تمام
What
ماذا؟
Huang Sir draws too fast
هذا السيد هوانغ يرسم بسرعة جنونية
The Flash
الرجل البرق
Can't just go for speed
مو بس المهم السرعة
Internet slang
مصطلح من الإنترنت
What?
إيش؟
Baby
يا حبيبي
Baby's tummy is rumbling
بطن البيبي صارت تزمجر
What the heck?
وش هالشيء؟
What is this?
إيش هذا؟
I don't know what this is either
حتى أنا ما أدري إيش هذا
This is indeed internet slang
هذا فعلًا تعبير من الإنترنت
Hard to say if it's popular
إذا هو رائج ولا لا، صعب نقول
Hungry, right?
جعت، صح؟
Yes
نعم
Close enough
تقريبًا
But it has a "baby" in it
بس فيه “بيبي”
Tummy is rumbling
وبطنه تزمجر
That one
يعني...
Whose baby
بيبي مين هذا
talks like that?
يتكلم كذا؟
Does he have anything to eat?
عنده شي يأكله؟
Can't wait to draw
متحمّس يرسم بسرعة مرة
Doesn't look like it
رسمه ما يشبه
Two words
كلمتان
"Kill" donkey
“ذبح” حمار
Knife Horse
داو ما
How did they guess it?
كيف خلّيتهم يخمّنونها؟
I'm drawing this here
أنا هنا أرسم هذا
Jingyu's is...
حق جينغ يو هو...
This one is fine
هذا ما فيه مشكلة
This works
هذا ينفع
This is no problem
هذا تمام
They can definitely guess this
هذا أكيد بيخمنونه
What does this mean?
وش معنى هذا؟
Chengcheng did a dance
فان تشنغ تشنغ رقص رقصة
A dance
رقصة
Knife Horse
داو ما
What the heck is this?
وش هالشيء؟
How do I draw this?
كيف نرسم هذا؟
Copy the drawing
انسخ الرسم
Just copy it
انسخها نسخًا حرفيًا
Just draw what you think
ارسم على طريقتك
Right, believe in yourself
نعم، ثق بنفسك
It's okay, we can look at theirs
عادي، نقدر نشوف رسمهم
How do I draw this?
هذا كيف ينرسم؟
Xiao Hu, hurry up.
شياو هو، أسرع
Xiao Hu, a little faster.
شياو هو، أسرع شوي
Show it to us secretly.
ورّينا بسرّ
No rush.
لا تستعجل
Let Jingyu reveal his work first.
خلّوا جينغ يو يطلع عمله أولًا
You're done drawing already?
خلصت الرسم كذا؟
Let's see.
خلّنا نشوف
These are the meanings of four separate characters.
هذه معاني أربع كلمات كل وحدة لحال
Adult?
سيدي
What is that thing?
وش هالشيء؟
What is "seven six"?
وش “سبعة ستة”؟
It's also four characters.
برضه أربع كلمات
Guess based on the image.
خمنوا من الشكل
Water and fire don't mix?
الماء والنار لا يجتمعان
Boiled...
مسلوق بالماء
Boiled what?
مسلوق إيش؟
Boiled frog?
ضفدع مسلوق بالماء
What is this thing?
وش هذا الشيء؟
A plate, a spoon.
طبق، ملعقة
Boiled frog?
ضفدع مسلوق بالماء
Boiled Pork Slices?
شرائح لحم مسلوقة بالماء
Correct.
نعم
That's right.
صح
Explain it.
اشرح لنا
You explain it.
أنت اشرح لنا
I really didn't see that was the character for "meat."
فعلاً ما قدرت أشوف إنها كلمة “لحم”
Brother Jingyu.
يا أخ جينغ يو
We were wondering...
نحن نبي...
what those two people were.
وش هالاثنين؟
I wrote there...
أنا كتبت هناك
what is "adult"?
وش يعني “سيدي”؟
Water.
ماء
Boiled.
سلق
I can kind of see that now.
هذا بدأ يبان شوي
You can't write characters.
ممنوع تكتب حروف
I drew a piece of meat.
أنا رسمت “لحم”
That's not...
هذا مو...
This...
هذا...
It just looks like it.
هو بس يشبه
But it's not a character.
بس مو حرف
You're starting to make up your own logic.
صار كل واحد...
Does this look like meat?
يشبه اللحم ولا لا؟
You call this a drawing?
تقول هذا رسم؟
Honestly, tell me what that thing is.
بصراحة، قل لي وش هذا الشيء؟
I still don't know what it is.
إلى الآن ما أدري وش هو
Water boiling something.
ماء يسلق شيئًا
Meat.
لحم
How do you draw "slice"?
كيف نرسم “شريحة”؟
I could only draw a leaf.
ما نقدر إلا نرسم ورقة شجر وحدة
"Slice" is really hard to draw.
“شريحة” فعلًا صعب تنرسم
"Slice," I get it.
شريحة، فهمت
Purely writing characters, right?
يعني كتابة بس، صح؟
Would you call that a character?
تقول هذا حرف؟
Not really.
مو حرف أصلًا
Look from a distance.
إذا شفتها من بعيد
Squint your eyes.
وغمّضت عيونك شوي
That is a "slice."
تصير “شريحة”
No, it's a combination of horizontal and vertical lines.
لا، هذا تركيب خطوط أفقية وعمودية
No.
لا
That's just the character "slice" written really badly.
هذا حرف “شريحة” مكتوب بشكل سيّئ جدًا
You can view it as a drawing.
اعتبروه رسمة وخلاص
Are there more questions?
فيه سؤال ثاني؟
I realized I have a bit of talent.
اكتشفت إن عندي موهبة بسيطة
Okay.
حسنًا
What is this at the front?
وش هذا اللي قدّام؟
Home.
بيت
Destitute with bare walls?
بيت فاضي إلا من الجدران
Wang Anyu.
وانغ آنيو
He wrote "Nothing at all."
كتب “لا يملك شيئًا”
Writing both Chinese and English.
كتب بالصيني وبالإنجليزي كمان
We can't write in English.
إحنا ما نقدر نكتب إنجليزي
These are all...
كل هذا...
No, regarding English...
لا، جزء الإنجليزي
They both have it, actually.
هم الاثنين عندهم هذا، صحيح
Right, our team has it too.
نعم، بيتنا بعد فيه
I wrote "Home."
أنا كتبت “بيت”
Our team has it too.
بيتنا بعد فيه
Go, Da Xi.
يلا، فرحة كبيرة
Come on, painter, come.
تعال يا رسّام، تعال
I can definitely do this one.
هذا أنا أكيد أقدر عليه
Okay.
تمام
Violent Bear
دبّ عنيف
Black bear
دبّ أعمى
Right, black bear
نعم، دبّ أعمى
He got it right
قالها صح
Brother Bing got it right
بيِنغ قالها صح
So fast
سريع جدًا
Drew it fast and well, Jin Chen
ترسمين بسرعة وبإتقان، جين تشن
You bet
طبعًا
What is that, Anyu
وش هذا اللي عندك، وانغ آنيو؟
No
لا
The key is he drew two
هو المهم رسم شيئين
What does that mean, Anyu
وش تقصد، وانغ آنيو؟
Bear
دبّ
Blind
أعمى
Too complicated
معقّد جدًا
For the sake of aesthetics
عشان تطلع الرسمة حلوة
You sacrificed speed
ضحّيت بالسرعة
It's not aesthetic either, that's the thing
وهي مو حلوة أصلًا، الأهم
You really know how to hype it up
أنت فعلًا تعرف تجامل
Ready
جاهزين
So complicated
يا له من تعقيد!
Water-injected meat
لحم محقون بالماء
Injection
حقنة
Doctor a dead horse as if it were alive
يعالج الميت كأنه حي
Wang Anyu
وانغ آنيو
Show your horse again
ورّينا حصانك مرة ثانية
I thought it was water-injected meat or something
حسبته لحمًا محقونًا بالماء أو شيء
I thought so too
وأنا كمان حسبته
Look at ours
شوفوا اللي عندنا
Dead horse, it died
حصان ميت، هو مات
Treat as a live horse
كأنه حصان حي
No, that is
لا، هذا
Jin Chen, that's a horse
جين تشن، هذا حصان
This is a dog
هذا كلب
Three characters
ثلاث كلمات
Dot mouth
نقطة على الفم
Mole by the mouth
شامة عند الفم
Five... Five mouths
خمسة... خمسة أفواه
Three characters
ثلاث كلمات
All talk
كلام فاضي
Big mute
أبكم كبير
Sand
رمل
Mouth
فم
Dense
كثيف
Crystal
بلّور
Messy
فوضى
Dot
نقطة
Scold
شتم
Dirty
قذر
Anyu, you just traced your drawing again
وانغ آنيو، أنت بس تتبّعت رسمتك
I really can't tell what it is
فعلاً ما أقدر أعرف وش هي
Can you add more detail
تقدر تضيف لها شوية؟
Pattern
نقش
Kill
قتل
Seal
ختم
Fire
نار
Floss
خيط تنظيف الأسنان
Draw a bit more, come on
ارسمها مرة ثانية طيب
Add a couple of strokes
ارسم خطّين بس
Just waiting
ننتظر وبس
You're the only one from the Art Academy
وأنت الوحيد من كلية فنون
And you can't even...
حتى... حتى الإضافة
Can't even add details, right
ما عاد تقدر تضيف، صح؟
Add two strokes
زِد خطّين
What is this now
وهذا وش بعد؟
We couldn't even tell what the first one was
الأول ما حد عرف وش هو
Wish you a birth...
أتمنى لك عيد ميلاد
Eat cake
تأكل كعكة
Birthday boy
صاحب عيد الميلاد
Happy birth...
عيد ميلاد سعي
What
ماذا؟
I really don't know how to connect them
ما عاد أعرف كيف أربطها
He gets it again
هو فهمها مرة ثانية
Aren't you afraid someone will copy it?
مو كنت تخاف أحد يقلّدك؟
Look at this.
شوف
Who would copy that drawing?
مين بيقلّد رسمتك؟
Hurry up.
أنت بسرعة
This needs to be viewed vertically, right?
لازم ننظر لها عموديًا، صح؟
Turn it.
اقلب
Broken.
مكسّر
Chatterbox.
ثرثار
Explain it.
اشرح لنا
Isn't this broken?
مو هذا مكسّر؟
Broken. Very broken.
مكسّر، مكسّر جدًا
Mouth.
فم
What's the difference between your "broken" and "Zi"?
طيب وش الفرق بين “مكسّر” و“زي”؟
The last character.
آخر حرف
What about "Zi"?
وش فيها “زي”؟
This is...
هذا
This is a Go piece I drew. A piece.
هذه قطع لعبة خمس قطع اللي رسمتها
No, I couldn't just draw a son, could I?
لا، يعني ما أقدر أرسم “ابن”!
I originally wanted to draw a cake...
كنت ناوي أرسم هذه الكعكة
...to mean one year old, two years old...
أقول عمره سنة أو سنتين، يعني ذاك
But I didn't draw it clearly.
بس ما وضّحتها بالرسم
Because I really didn't know how to...
لأني فعلًا ما كنت أعرف كيف
"Chatterbox" really isn't that easy to draw.
“ثرثار” فعلًا مو سهل ينرسم
Right.
صح
And when you're on stage...
وبعدين لما تكون على المسرح
...you aren't that relaxed.
ما تكون مرتاح لهالدرجة
So your drawings are all pretty... you know.
عشان كذا رسوماتك كلها كذا
I know you're going up soon.
أعرف إنك بعد شوي بتطلع
No need.
لا داعي
I'm trying to smooth things over for you.
أنا بس أغطّي عليك
Melon seeds.
بزر
Seven characters.
سبع كلمات
Lost the watermelon, picked up the sesame.
ترك البطيخ وأخذ السمسم
I'm starting to get into...
أنا الحين بدأت أدخل
...his system of drawing.
في نظامه بالرسم
I can understand him now.
صرت أفهمه الحين
Come on.
خلّك بس
Did you also study at some art academy?
أنت كمان درست في كلية فنون؟
You could join the "Yuyao Academy of Fine Arts."
تقدر تنضم لـ“كلية فنون يوياو”
Yes.
نعم
It's starting to become...
كأنه بيصير
...like the "Head Disciple of the Wang School."
بمعنى “أكبر تلميذ لمدرسة وانغ”
I'm starting to appreciate it.
بدأت أقدّرها شوي
This should be a watermelon.
المفروض يرسم بطيخة
Alright.
خلاص
No need to enrich that drawing anymore.
ما يحتاج تزيد على هذيك الرسمة
Lost the sesame, picked up the watermelon.
ترك السمسم وأخذ البطيخ
Lost the watermelon, picked up...
ترك البطيخ وأخذ
Lost the watermelon.
ترك البطيخ
Then that person is pretty smart.
أجل هذا الشخص ذكي
We give up on this one.
نستسلم في هذا السؤال
How many characters?
كم كلمة؟
Emperor.
الإمبراطور
Your Majesty.
جلالة الإمبراطور
Press it quick, Sister Daxi.
اضغطي بسرعة يا أخت داشي!
Press it quick.
اضغط بسرعة
Shen Teng.
شين تينغ
Concubine.
محظية
Husband and wife.
زوجان
Noble Consort. Concubine.
محظية كبرى، محظيات
This is a concubine. Empress.
هذه محظية... الإمبراطورة
Press it quick.
اضغط بسرعة
Anyu.
وانغ آنيو
Press.
اضغط
Husband.
زوجي
How did you guess "Husband"?
كيف خمنتِ أنها “زوجي”؟
How on earth did you guess that?
كيف خمنتها بالضبط؟
Bai Jingting.
باي جينغ تينغ
You can join the "Yuyao Academy of Fine Arts."
تقدر تنضم إلى “أكاديمية يوياو للفنون”.
How did you guess it?
كيف عرفتِ؟
During that song yesterday...
وقت أغنية أمس.
...wasn't Brother Teng saying "Husband, Husband" all the time?
أليس شين تينغ كان يكرر “زوجي، زوجي”؟
Husband, Husband.
زوجي، زوجي
You called the Emperor "Husband."
تنادين الإمبراطور “زوجي”.
But you have to admit...
بس بصراحة،
...your drawing of the Emperor really looks like him.
رسمك للإمبراطور طلع فعلاً يشبهه.
Right?
صح؟
I got married.
أنا كذا كأني تزوجت.
Calling "Husband" on the wedding night.
ليلة الزفاف تناديه “زوجي”.
Nothing wrong with that.
تمام، ما فيها شي.
What is that?
وش هذا اللي عندك؟
Emperor. Cold Palace.
الإمبراطور، القصر البارد.
This one.
هذا.
Hitting high notes
يطلع نغمة عالية.
"Thinking of Your Night"
“ليلة اشتياقي لك”
Bai Jingting
باي جينغ تينغ
That's really impressive
فعلاً رهيب!
That microphone
ذاك الميكروفون.
I was thinking
فقلت لنفسي،
Since he drew the microphone so confidently
إذا يرسم ميكروفون بثقة كذا،
It must be related to him
أكيد له علاقة فيه.
That "Thinking of Your Night"
وأغنية “ليلة اشتياقي لك”.
That arrow for the high note
السهم حقه على النغمة العالية.
I could actually hear it
أنا حتى سمعته!
Thinking of your
أشتاق لك
Night
ليلة
Thinking of your night
ليلة اشتياقي لك
How I wish you were by my side
يا ليتك تكون بجانبي.
When did you become a group?
متى صرنا فرقة؟
Jin Chen, what did you draw?
جين تشن، إيش اللي رسمتيه؟
Because the eight of us are sitting here
لأننا الثمانية جالسين هنا،
And he's singing by himself
وهو يغني لحاله.
Thinking of your night
ليلة اشتياقي لك
And we were all like question marks
ونحن كلنا علامات استفهام.
Junior brother
يا زميلي الصغير،
Leave it to you
الموضوع عندك.
Wetland
الأراضي الرطبة
We went there yesterday too
رحنا لها أمس بعد.
With the two of us here
طالما نحن الاثنين موجودين،
We've won
فزنا.
How could we lose?
كيف نخسر؟
You guys are from the same system
أنتم من نفس النظام.
You can't guess each other's
ما ينفع تخمنون لبعض!
Come on, bro
شد حيلك يا أخي.
How many characters?
كم كلمة؟
What?
ماذا؟
Invisible Wi...
جناح خفي...
Invisible Wings
الأجنحة الخفية
Long legs
ساقان طويلتان
Long-legged girl
فتاة بساقين طويلتين
Breaking the cocoon into a butterfly
الخروج من الشرنقة لتصبح فراشة
Four characters
أربع كلمات.
Boxing training
تدريب ملاكمة
What shadow?
أي ظل؟
Swaying back and forth
يميل يمين ويسار.
Did you guess it from mine?
أكيد عرفها من اللي رسمته أنا.
Definitely guessed it from mine
مئة بالمئة عرفها من رسمي.
Let me see
خلني أشوف.
We had the same train of thought
نفس الفكرة عندنا.
His has that swaying shadow
هو عنده ظل يهتز كذا.
At the beginning
في البداية،
Right, I drew a shadow with two heads
صح، أنا رسمت ظل برأسين.
Swung too fast
هزّها بسرعة مرة.
"Ice Rain"
“مطر جليدي”
Wang Anyu
وانغ آنيو
The cold ice rain pats wildly on my face
مطر جليدي بارد يصفع وجهي بعشوائية.
Pats wildly on my face
يصفع وجهي بعشوائية.
What?
ماذا؟
Guess quickly
يلا خمن بسرعة!
Guess!
خمن بسرعة!
Did you accidentally drop your pen on it?
هذا مو كأنه قلم طاح بالغلط؟
Ice shards
قطع ثلج.
"Ice Rain"
“مطر جليدي”
Now that is wisdom
هذا اللي اسمه ذكاء!
That's awesome
مذهل!
I'm impressed
استسلمت، ما شاء الله.
Their wavelengths match perfectly
نفس المستوى، متطابقين تمامًا.
We're from the same school, of course
نحن من نفس المدرسة، طبيعي!
Next question
السؤال اللي بعده.
Gold ingot
سبيكة ذهب.
Ingot
سبيكة.
That
ذاك...
Hot pot
هوت بوت.
Three characters
ثلاث كلمات.
Guess
خمن!
Golden Kick
ثلاثي الأرجل الذهبي
Next is purely
اللي جاي كله
An artistic duel
مواجهة فنية صافية.
Okay
تمام.
I know the answer
عرفت الجواب.
Four characters
أربع كلمات.
Is it a butt?
هل هو مؤخرة؟
How could you think of
كيف خطر ببالك في البرنامج
Asking that on the show?
تسأل سؤال زي كذا؟
Wild goose
إوز بري.
That
ذاك...
What?
ماذا؟
Flying south
يطير جنوبًا.
Is it a swallow?
هل هي سنونو؟
Look at his to guess mine
شوف رسمه وقل لي عن رسمي.
Wild geese return to roots
عودة الإوز إلى موطنه
Falling leaves return to their roots
عودة الورق إلى جذوره
A clumsy bird flies first
الطائر الغبي يطير أولًا
Where is it clumsy?
وين الغباء فيه؟
That mouth
هذا الفم...
Just now, Wang Anyu
قبل شوي وانغ آنيو
was doing this
كان يسوي كذا.
So that's how I drew it
عشان كذا رسمته بهذا الشكل.
It looks a bit more dopey
يطلع أغبى شوي.
So this at the bottom is me
فهذا اللي تحت هو أنا.
The one flying first is me
اللي طار أولًا أنا.
You... He pouted at me just now
هو قبل شوي زمّ شفتيه لي.
I said
فقلت:
How do you draw a clumsy bird?
كيف أرسم “الطائر الغبي”؟
And then
وبعدين...
My train of thought
طريقة تفكيري
can't keep up at all anymore
صارت ما تلحق أبدًا، خلاص.
I've been completely left behind
انفصلت عنكم تمامًا.
I'm barely hanging on now
أنا الحين بالكاد
I feel like
أحس
I racked my brains
عصرت مخي عصر،
and came up with a word
وطلعت بكلمة واحدة.
Leg workout
تمرين الساقين
Legs, dumbbells
ساق، دمبل.
Accurate
صحيح.
Is it as accurate as mine?
أدق مني فيه؟
What is it?
وش هو؟
Barre
عارضة الباليه
When I was young at the Children's Palace
وأنا صغير في مركز الشباب،
I suffered so much
تعبت كثير.
training legs on the barre every day
كل يوم أتمرن ساقيني على العارضة.
Those aren't the same kind of leg training
هم الاثنين مو نفس “تمرين الساقين”.
Your team member fell asleep
عضو فريقكم نام!
What's wrong? Stumped?
وش فيه؟ انحشرتوا؟
I really don't know this one
هالسؤال فعلًا ما أعرفه.
Grand salute
أداء التحية الكبرى
Three characters
ثلاث كلمات.
Milky Way
مجرة درب التبانة
Respect the sun and moon
تبجيل الشمس والقمر
Majesty sun moon, Emperor
جلالة الشمس والقمر، الإمبراطور
Auspicious day
يوم ميمون
Yellow sun moon
هوانغ شمس قمر
Huang Taiyue
هوانغ القمر العظيم
Yellow sun
هوانغ الشمس
Guess
خمن
Moon
قمر
Donkey
حمار
Three characters
ثلاث كلمات
Weasel
ابن عرس
Qin Shi Huang
إمبراطور تشين الأول
What was added?
وش أضفت؟
Huang what?
هوانغ ماذا؟
Yellow bird
طائر أصفر
Chicken
دجاجة
Yellow chicken
دجاجة صفراء
Bird
طائر
Crow
غراب
Oriole
طائر الصفّار
It's still this
ما زال هذا
It's still the same
ما زال نفسه
Move a little
تحرّك قليلًا
Huang Jingyu
هوانغ جينغ يو
Huang Sir
السيد هوانغ
Huang
هوانغ
Number Four
الرابع
Huang Yueying
هوانغ يويه ينغ
Huang Taiyue
هوانغ القمر العظيم
Huang Riyue
هوانغ شمس قمر
Huang Xiaoming
هوانغ شياو مينغ
Sun and moon make "Ming"
الشمس والقمر يضيئان
Where is "Xiao"?
أين “شياو”؟
This size
هذا الحجم
I drew a "big" here
أنا رسمت واحدًا كبيرًا
And this is "small"
وهذا صغير
I'm pointing at "small"
أقصد الصغير
What's the first one? Huang?
الأول ما هو؟ هوانغ؟
"Huang" is...
هوانغ يعني...
The "Majesty" drawn up there
ذاك “الجلالة” الذي رسموه فوق
A homophone, homophone
تلاعب لفظي، تلاعب لفظي
No, Brother Teng's is...
لا، حق تنغ هذا...
Brother Teng, tell us about the big bow
تنغ، قل لنا عن “التحية الكبرى” ذاك
No, I wanted to draw Brother Xiaoming's
لا، أنا أبي أرسم حق أخ شياو مينغ
Xiaoming, I'm sorry
شياو مينغ، آسف
Then the middle one is...
طيب، اللي بالنص هو...
This is from his music video
هذا حق مقطعه الموسيقي القصير
It really is
طلع فعلًا
Cry
بكاء
What's that donkey next to it?
طيب الحمار اللي جنبها هذا شنو؟
Big yellow dog
الكلب الأصفر الكبير
How can you tell that's "Big Yellow"?
كيف عرفت إنه “الأصفر الكبير”؟
"Xiao" from size, rooster crowing
الصغير بالحجم، والدجاج يصيح
This is too abstract
هذا تجريدي جدًا
Brother Xiaoming
أخ شياو مينغ
No offense intended
سامحنا على الإزعاج
Sorry about that
آسف
This question is really...
هذا السؤال بصراحة...
No
لا
This question is indeed tricky
هذا السؤال فعلًا صعب
Sorry
آسف
Offense
إزعاج
Why is this game so intense?
ليش اللعبة صارت حماسية لهالدرجة؟
Flying car
سيارة طائرة
Three words
ثلاث كلمات
Husband
زوجي
Chatterbox
ثرثار
"The Night I Miss You"
“ليلة أشتاق إليك”
Bai Jingting
باي جينغ تينغ
"Ice Rain"
“مطر جليدي”
Golden Tripod
القدم الذهبية الثلاثية
Huang Xiaoming
هوانغ شياو مينغ
You don't get me, Wang Anyu
أنت ما تفهمني، وانغ آنيو
You disappoint me so much
أنت خيّبت أملي كثيرًا
Guess again
يلا خمنوا مرة ثانية
Get into the situation
تخيلوا نفسكم في هذا الموقف
Where is this?
هذا وين نحطه؟
Above the clouds
فوق الغيوم
Car on clouds
سيارة فوق الغيوم
The car has a big glass pane
على السيارة لوح زجاج كبير
Three words
ثلاث كلمات
I know
أنا أعرف
Is this what you drew?
أقول، أنت رسمت هالشي ولا لا؟
Figure it out yourself
فكّر أنت
Sightseeing car, tour car, little flying car
سيارة سياحية، سيارة جولة، سيارة طيران صغيرة
Racing car
سيارة سباق
Small electric car
عربة كهربائية صغيرة
No, it's on the clouds, in the sky
لا، هي فوق الغيوم، في السما
Car in the sky
السيارة في السما
Hover car
سيارة معلّقة
Xiao Bai is distorted
شياو باي حتى تشوّه
Car
سيارة
Taxi
سيارة أجرة
Three words total. Taxi
هي ثلاث كلمات: سيارة أجرة
Out
خروج
Rent
إيجار
Isn't that just a car?
مو هي سيارة وخلاص؟
I got it
عرفت
Man-woman car
سيارة رجال ونساء
Woman
امرأة
What kind of car has a man and a woman?
رجل وامرأة بسيارة واحدة، أي سيارة؟
Pig
خنزير
Driving a taxi
يسوق سيارة أجرة
Driving a pig
يسوق خنزير
No, I...
لا، أنا...
What is this again?
وهذا شنو بعد؟
Two drawings
رسمتان
Dance
رقص
Taxi
إيجار
Stop saying taxi. Don't rent anymore.
لا تؤجر بعد، لا تؤجر
Car
سيارة
What are you doing?
وش تسوون؟
Dancing
يرقص
Dancing car
سيارة رقص
Dance car
سيارة للرقص
Watching a float
شاهد عربة الاستعراض
Doing the Yangge
يرقص يانغغه
Xiao Bai
شياو باي
Also... how else can I do this?
بعد؟ وش باقي نسوي؟
Even harder to understand
صار أقل فهمًا
Rental house
شقة للإيجار
How can you tell that's a rental house?
كيف عرفت إنها شقة للإيجار؟
Isn't that a floor lamp?
مو هذا مصباح أرضي؟
There's really no...
بصراحة ما...
Which one is a floor lamp?
أي واحد هو المصباح الأرضي؟
The table next to it
الطاولة اللي جنبها
That floor lamp
ذاك المصباح الأرضي
This is a floor lamp
هذا مصباح أرضي
That is a fl...
ذاك هو...
Isn't this a popsicle?
مو هذا آيس كريم على عصا؟
Yeah
إيه
Popsicle
آيس كريم على عصا
Darn it
انتهينا
What's that next to it?
وش هذا اللي جنبه؟
Fried egg
بيضة مقلية
Fried popsicle
بيضة وآيس كريم على عصا
What is this?
إيش هذا؟
Person
شخص.
How does this compare to that?
وهذا مقارنةً به، إيش فيه؟
Compare what?
مقارنةً به إيش؟
What's on top of this?
وإيش اللي فوق هذا؟
Don't worry about what this is for now
لا تهتم الآن إيش هذا.
I'm asking you, what's the relationship between them?
أنا بس أسألك: إيش العلاقة بين الاثنين؟
One big, one small
واحد كبير وواحد صغير.
Is this one big, one small?
هذا كبير وصغير فعلًا؟
Did I draw a distance relationship?
أنا رسمت لك علاقة قرب وبُعد؟
It's on the ground, it's in the sky
واحد على الأرض وواحد في السماء.
This is relative
هذا نسبي.
This
هذا...
What is this?
إيش هذا؟
Car
سيارة.
This is a car
هذه سيارة.
What car has this on top?
أي سيارة يكون فوقها هذا؟
Police car
سيارة شرطة.
Taxi
ـ
Then
وبعدين...
Taxi dance
رقصة الـ...
Almost there
تقريبًا كذا.
Disco
ديسكو.
Correct
صح!
This was really too hard to draw
هذا فعلًا صعب جدًا ينرسم.
Taxi
تاكسي.
High up in the clouds
عالي فوق الغيوم.
Disco
ديسكو.
Mine was too
وأنا كمان.
The hat on top of the taxi is high
القبعة فوق التاكسي عالية.
The place where "Taxi" is written is high
ومكان كلمة “تاكسي” مرتفع.
I forgot about this
هذا نسيته.
I drew a pig taxi
رسمت سيارة “إخراج خنازير”.
This is obviously a taxi
واضح إنها تاكسي!
Pig car
سيارة خنازير.
Pig out
إخراج خنازير.
I forgot, my drawing went off topic
نسيت، الرسم طلع عن الموضوع.
For the first time in my life
أول مرة بحياتي
I managed to draw someone going out clearly
أقدر أرسم واحد طالع من البيت بشكل مفهوم.
Is this "Low"?
هذا يعني “منخفض”؟
This is a persimmon
هذه فاكهة كاكي.
Persimmon
كاكي.
This is ice cream
هذا آيس كريم.
Then when he said popsicle, you shouldn't have said yes
إذا قال “مصاصة ثلج” ما كان لازم تقول صح.
We were wondering what kind of stick
كنا طول الوقت نفكر: أي “عصا”؟
You know?
فاهم؟
Then I wouldn't...
طيب وأنا بعد...
I only drew...
أنا أصلًا ما رسمت إلا...
Later
وبعدين
Low
منخفض.
"Si" High
“ميت” عالي.
I really had no choice
والله ما عاد عندي حيلة.
I even drew the dance out
حتى الرقصة رسمتها!
This move
هذي الحركة.
These were actually pretty good
هذي كم وحدة حلوة بصراحة.
But you couldn't guess it
بس ما قدرتوا تتوقعون.
You'd never guess this "Si"
حتى “ميت” ما توقعتوه.
Anyu really did the first move just now
قبل شوي وانغ آنيو فعلًا سوّى أول حركة.
He didn't continue
بس ما كمل بعدها.
He really did the first move
هو فعلًا سوّى أول حركة.
Hailing a taxi
نطلب تاكسي.
You're just too fancy
أنت متأنّق زيادة بصراحة.
We usually don't call it "Di Shi"
إحنا عادة ما نقول “تاكسي”.
Then "Di"
طيب الـ...
I thought for ages, how else to draw "Di"
قعدت أفكر طويلًا كيف أرسم “الـ”.
The simplest and clearest way
أبسط شيء وأوضح شيء
Is right here
هو موجود هنا.
And you still couldn't guess it
ومع كذا ما قدرتوا تخمّنوا!
Your persimmon
فاكهة الكاكي اللي عندك...
Your "Shi" really wasn't recognizable either
وكلمة “تاكسي” عندك فعلًا ما تنفهم.
My persimmon
أما كاكي حقي...
This part is the little stem
وهذا الجزء هو الخصلة اللي فوق.
What is this?
إيش هذا؟
This is the position height
هذا يوضح الارتفاع والانخفاض.
But this is hard
بس هذا صعب جدًا.
It's really hard to guess it's "Di"
فعلاً صعب تخمّن إنه “الـ”.
It really is hard
فعلاً صعب.
Our final result is
النتيجة النهائية هي:
Six to sixteen
6 مقابل 16.
A narrow victory
فوز بصعوبة.
You call that a narrow victory?
وهذا بعد يسمّونه فوز بصعوبة؟
Congratulations to Anyu's team
مبروك لمجموعة وانغ آنيو.
For winning the chance to swap campsites
فازوا بفرصة تبديل المخيم.
Let's stay in the good one together
خلّونا نسكن سوا، تمام؟
Cooking, cooking
نطبخ، نطبخ!
I'll stew one dish and stir-fry one
بس بسوي طبخة مطبوخة وطبخة مقلية.
Make some noodles and that's it
ونسوي نودلز وخلاص.
Brother Bing, are you stir-frying now or...
يا “أخوي بينغ”، بتقلي الآن ولا...
I'm prepping
أنا أجهّزها.
This oil smells amazing
هذا الزيت ريحته فظيعة من الطيب.
Stew some beans
نطبخ فاصوليا خضراء.
What are you doing?
إيش تبغى تسوي؟
Make it smoked flavor
تبغاه يصير بطعم مدخّن؟
My knees are cold
ركبتي بردانة.
I want to stick my knees in there
أبغى أدخل ركبتي جوّا.
That's really wicked
يا لك من عديم الذوق!
I'll try to stand nearby
بحاول أوقف قريب من هنا.
If I catch fire at any point
إذا اشتعلت متى...
Tell me
قولي على طول.
I'm smoking
أنا أطلع دخان.
You can't tell if the pot is smoking
ما يبان إذا الدخان من القدر
Or if you are smoking
ولا منك أنت.
Don't get yourself burned
لا تنشوي أنت.
It's really too late
ما عاد في وقت فعلًا.
I asked him to watch out for me
خلّيته يراقب لي.
Tell me if I catch fire
إذا اشتعلت، قولي فورًا.
You even assigned such a...
وترسل لي واحد
Actor of this caliber
بمستوى ممثل كذا!
To watch that for you
عشان يراقب لك هذا.
To see if you get singed, right?
عشان يشوف احترقت ولا لا، صح؟
Isn't he standing nearby too?
هو أصلًا واقف قريب، مو؟
What are you making?
إيش تسوون؟
Kung Pao Chicken
دجاج كونغ باو.
Kung Pao Chicken, okay
دجاج كونغ باو، تمام.
Go ask Brother Bing how the food is coming along
روح اسأل “أخوي بينغ” كيف صار الطبخ.
Showing off in front of me, huh?
تسوي حركات علينا إحنا الاثنين، صح؟
Showing off.
حركات.
What kind of move is this?
إيش هذي الحركة؟
Bro, I'm here to check it out.
يا أخي، جيت أشوف.
Is it okay?
تمام؟
It's pretty good.
تمام جدًا.
How do we mess with this?
كيف بتخربها؟
Let you taste some authentic...
خلّك تذوق الأصلي على أصوله.
Old Beijing Kung Pao Chicken.
دجاج كونغ باو على طريقة بكين القديمة.
The kind restaurants sell for 288.
اللي بالمطعم يبيعونه بـ288.
Looks the part.
شكله مرتب.
Hot wok, cold oil.
مقلاة حامية وزيت بارد.
Ready to serve.
طلع من القدر.
Kung Pao Chicken.
دجاج كونغ باو.
Success or failure depends on this.
النجاح أو الفشل في هالخطوة.
Kung Pao Chicken is here.
وصل دجاج كونغ باو!
You made this?
أنت اللي سويته؟
I made it.
أنا اللي سويته.
Let me try a bite.
خلّني أذوق لقمة.
I'll take a seat first.
أنا بقعد أولًا.
It's a bit spicy.
فيه شوية حرّ.
Have a taste.
ذوق لقمة.
It's delicious, Bro.
لذيذ يا أخي
Delicious. Really delicious.
لذيذ، لذيذ فعلًا
Delicious.
لذيذ
I can't stop eating.
صرت ما أقدر أوقف شوي
It's definitely not just encouragement.
مو تشجيع أبدًا
But...
بل
But an honest evaluation.
بل تقييم منصف
I'll make it for you again next time.
المرة الجاية بسويه لكم بعد
Every meal from now on will be this.
ومن اليوم كل وجبة بتكون كذا
You're not allowed to eat Brother Bing's dish.
ممنوع تاكلون أكل بيغو
I'm telling you, this is truly...
أقولها بجد، فعلًا
The best Kung Pao Chicken I've ever had.
أطيب دجاج كونغ باو ذقته بحياتي
Just a little bit spicy.
بس حار شوي
Brother Teng.
تينغو
Brother Teng, have a taste.
تينغو، ذوق
Really, tell me.
صدق، قل لي
Our ingredients in Qiqihar are really good.
مكونات تشيتشيهار عندنا رهيبة
The ingredients are indeed nice.
المكونات فعلًا ممتازة
Really delicious.
لذيذ جدًا
Really.
والله صدق
Stir-fry one.
اقلي واحد
Just chili and cucumber is enough.
فلفل وخيار يكفي
It goes so well with rice.
يفتح النفس على الأكل مرة
Come on.
يلا
Cook some noodles too.
واسلقوا نودلز كمان
Who disagrees?
مين مو مقتنع؟
Come battle. Come on.
تعال نتحدّى، تعال
This is awesome. Watch this.
هذا خرافي، شوفوا
Jin Chen, come here.
جين تشن، تعالي
Jin Chen.
جين تشن
What?
ها؟
One...
واحد
One bowl per person.
كل واحد له زبدية
I can't handle a whole bowl.
أنا ما أقدر آخذ زبدية كاملة
Just a few strands is fine.
كم عود بس يكفي
If you can't finish it...
أجل ما بتقدر تاكل
You give it to him.
عطيه هو ياكل
If you can't finish, pour it in my flask.
إذا ما تقدر، صبّه لي بالإبريق
I'll take it back with me.
آخذه معي
You two.
إنتوا الاثنين
You two go first.
إنتوا الاثنين تعالوا أول
You two come here.
إنتوا الاثنين تعالوا
You two go share a bowl quickly.
إنتوا الاثنين بسرعة اقتسموا زبدية
Eat up.
تفضلوا كلوا
Okay, thanks.
تمام، شكرًا
You're welcome.
العفو
That's enough.
يكفي
Don't.
لا
No, no more.
لا، خلاص ما أبي
I'll serve myself.
خلّني أجهز لنفسي
Brother, you don't need chili oil for these noodles.
يا أخي، هالنودلز ما تحتاج زيت فلفل
Chili oil changes the flavor.
زيت الفلفل يغيّر الطعم
Understood.
فهمت
Is it okay? This taste.
تمام هالطعم؟
It's so delicious.
لذيذ بشكل مو طبيعي
Why do these noodles taste better the more I eat?
ليش كل ما آكلها تصير ألذ؟
Why don't I have these culinary skills?
ليش ما عندي هالمهارة بالطبخ؟
These potatoes are incredible.
هالبطاطس خرافية
Bing Ge.
بيغو
When it comes to Northeast cuisine,
بأكل الشمال الشرقي
he's really unbeatable now.
صار ما له منافس الحين
Really?
صدق؟
The key is,
والأهم
Bing Ge cooks fast too.
بيغو يطبخ بسرعة بعد
Right.
صح
He can cook so many dishes at the same time.
هو الوحيد يقدر يسوي أطباق كثيرة مع بعض
And for every single one,
وكل طبق
the heat control is just right.
ونضجه مضبوط تمام
That's so difficult.
هذا صعب جدًا
I've been curious for a while.
وأنا مستغرب من زمان
This dish is refreshing chili peppers...
هالطبق فلفل حار منعش
and spicy cucumbers.
ومعه خيار حار مرة
Spicy.
صار حار مرة
They say...
يقولون إنه
They say it's a famous Tianjin dish.
يقولون إنه طبق مشهور من تيانجين
No.
لا
It's not.
مو صحيح
Tianjin doesn't have this.
تيانجين ما عندها هالشي
What do you know?
إيش تعرف أنت؟
In Tianjin, you only eat Jianbing.
أنت بتيانجين ما تاكل إلا فطيرة جيانبنغ
Slander.
افتراء!
I'm so full.
شبعت مرة
I ate too much.
أكلت كثير
When I go back these couple of days...
هاليومين إذا رجعت
after we finish eating at night,
بعد ما خلصنا أكل الليل ذاك
I don't really digest it when I get back.
حتى رجعت وما هضمته زين
That belly...
هالبطن
cries in front of the mirror every night.
كل ليلة تبكي قدام المراية
The belly cries by itself.
بطني هو اللي يبكي
It hugs me and cries.
تحضني وتبكي
My...
أنا هذا
this down jacket is basically...
هالجاكيت الريشي كأنه
burnt.
انشوى وانحرق
No, I just came from over there.
لا، توّي جاي من هناك
I brushed against this.
لمس هذا شوي
Put those feathers in a plastic bag.
ذاك الوبر حطّوه بكيس بلاستيك
Don't waste them.
لا تضيّعونه
Go back and make a pair of cotton pants.
ارجعوا سوّوا منه سروال قطن
What did you go do?
وين رحت؟
Washed my hands.
غسلت يدي
Whatever you do, don't touch that pipe.
إياك تلمس ذاك الأنبوب
The second victim.
الضحية الثانية
Even the shape is the same.
حتى الشكل نفسه
I can't return this jacket now.
هالملابس ما بترجع مثل أول
Have to pay a fortune to buy it.
لازم نشتري غيرها بمبلغ كبير
Pay a fortune.
شراء بمبلغ كبير
I'd rather freeze to "death" myself.
أفضل أتجمد “للموت”
I wouldn't let...
ولا راح أخلي
the clothes I borrowed get ruined.
الملابس اللي استلفتها تخرب
I stay far away from the stove.
أنا أبعد عن الموقد كثير
I rarely come to the three Northeast provinces.
نادرًا أجي لمقاطعات الشمال الشرقي الثلاث
And the last time I came to the Northeast,
وآخر مرة جيت للشمال الشرقي
was to go to that...
كانت عشان أروح
I've only been to Harbin.
ما رحت إلا هاربين
So I haven't been to many Northeast cities.
وما زرت مدن كثيرة هناك
Qiqihar is one.
تشيتشيهار واحدة منها
A city that exceeded our expectations
مدينة فاقت توقعاتنا
In my impression
حسب ما أتذكر
This is my first time
هذه أول مرة لي
seeing that birch forest
أرى غابة البتولا تلك
It was stunning
كان الأمر مدهشًا جدًا
And very beautiful
وكمان جميلة جدًا
The scenery is just especially lovely
المناظر هنا جميلة بشكل خاص
And the rice paddies
وكمان هذا الأرز
It happens to be the harvest season
جاء تمامًا في موسم الحصاد
It's very meaningful
له معنى كبير
For me, this is like coming home
هذا بالنسبة لي كأني رجعت للبيت
I found the scenery from my childhood
لقيت المشهد اللي كان بذاكرتي من طفولتي
Especially every time we
خصوصًا كل مرة
head towards the suburbs
نطلع فيها للضواحي
on the way to every scenic spot
في الطريق لكل منطقة سياحية
Birch trees
أشجار البتولا
Big poplar trees
وأشجار الحور الكبيرة
Including those pine trees
وحتى أشجار الصنوبر
With dappled light shining through
من خلال بقع الضوء
The sky is so, so blue
السماء زرقاء زُرقة لا توصف
The air is so, so clear
والهواء نقي وشفاف جدًا
It instantly took me back to childhood
وفجأة رجعت لطفولتي
Maybe I'm getting older
يمكن لأني كبرت في السن
and really want to find past memories
صرت أشتاق جدًا لذكريات زمان
I found them in Qiqihar
ولقيتها في تشيتشيهار
Although I'm not from the Northeast
مع إني لست من الشمال الشرقي
but
لكن
I've filmed many works about the Northeast
صوّرت أعمالًا كثيرة عن الشمال الشرقي
In our previous drama
في مسلسلنا السابق
there's a song called "Northeast Folk Song"
كانت هناك أغنية اسمها “أغنية الشمال الشرقي الشعبية”
There's a lyric that goes
وفيها سطر يقول
The setting sun beyond the Great Wall is her red makeup
شمس الأصيل في الشمال هي حُمرتها
With pines and cypresses as bridesmaids
وجبلٌ من الصنوبر والسرو وصيفاتٌ لها
These past two days
هذين اليومين
seeing that sunset every day
كل يوم أرى ذلك الغروب
I feel that lyric
وأشعر أن ذلك السطر
has made every scene I see
حوّل كل ما أراه من مشاهد
become concrete
إلى صورة ملموسة أمامي
This season is very beautiful right now
هذا الموسم جميل جدًا
You can see
تقدر تشوف
golden yellow
الذهبي
green
والأخضر
blue sky
والسماء الزرقاء
this kind of blended beauty
هذا الجمال المتداخل بألوان كثيرة
I feel very lucky
أشعر أني محظوظ جدًا
to be able to feel
لأني أقدر أحس
the power within those lyrics
بقوة الكلمات في الأغنية
And Qiqihar right now
وبعدين تشيتشيهار الآن
is very suitable for camping
مناسبة جدًا للتخييم
I hope friends from the North
أتمنى أصدقاءنا في الشمال
can drive to Qiqihar
يجون بالسيارة إلى تشيتشيهار
to experience the barbecue here
ويجربون شواء تشيتشيهار
the scenery
والمناظر
and camping
والتخييم
Can Southerners come?
وأهل الجنوب يقدرون يجون؟
Southerners can fly here
أهل الجنوب يجيون بالطائرة
It's my first time in Qiqihar
هذه أول مرة أزور تشيتشيهار
And
وبصراحة
it's not quite what I imagined
طلعت مختلفة عن اللي تخيلته
It's just
يعني
very big
كبيرة جدًا
and very good-looking
وجميلة جدًا
The air is also especially good
والهواء فيها ممتاز جدًا
I hope everyone can
أتمنى أن يقدر الجميع
come take a look at Qiqihar
يجي إلى تشيتشيهار ويلقي نظرة
have some fun, eat some food
ويتمشّى شوي ويأكل شوي
It's really great
شيء رائع جدًا
I think it's very fun
أشوفها ممتعة جدًا
Brother Teng's hometown feels
أحسّ مسقط رأس الأخ تنغ
especially welcoming
حماسي وودود جدًا
Come
يلا
I hope to have the chance to come again
أتمنى نرجع لها مرة ثانية إذا سنحت الفرصة
It's also my first time in Qiqihar
وأنا كمان أول مرة أجي تشيتشيهار
I've always known people from Qiqihar
طول عمري أعرف ناسًا من تشيتشيهار
A very good senior
واحد منهم أستاذ كبير ومحترم
But I hadn't
لكن ما
hadn't truly stepped into Qiqihar
قد دخلت تشيتشيهار فعلًا وتعرّفت عليها
But after coming to Qiqihar
بس لما جيت تشيتشيهار
I found so much beautiful scenery
اكتشفت إن فيها مناظر حلوة كثير
and delicious food
وأكلات لذيذة
The pickled cabbage is amazing
والمخلّل الحامض رهيب جدًا
Thank you, Brother Teng
شكرًا يا أخ تنغ
for taking such good care of everyone this time
اهتمّ بالجميع هالمرة بشكل ممتاز
It was very comfortable
وخلّى كل شيء مريح جدًا
I hope there will be a chance
أتمنى تكون فيه فرصة ثانية
to come to Qiqihar again
نرجع فيها لتشيتشيهار
And
وبعدها
bring more good friends along
نجيب معنا أصدقاء أكثر ونجي سوا
to experience
ونروح نحسّ
the local culture and scenery
بجمال المكان وثقافته هنا
And
وبعدها
I also want to recommend Qiqihar to everyone
حاب كمان أوصيكم بتشيتشيهار
I hope everyone can come to Qiqihar
أتمنى الكل يجي لتشيتشيهار
to feel this place's
ويجرّب إحساس هالمكان
happy, enthusiastic
الفرِح والحماسي
Northeast atmosphere
أجواء الشمال الشرقي
Okay
تمام
I am from the Northeast.
أنا من الشمال الشرقي
But I also
بس أنا كمان
haven't been to Qiqihar.
ما قد جيت تشيتشيهار
My overall feeling...
بشكل عام إحساسي
Actually, in the Northeast,
بصراحة الشمال الشرقي
many city buildings look alike.
كثير من مدنه مبانيها متشابهة
When you go to the Northeast,
لما تروح للشمال الشرقي
and you see many houses
وتشوف بيوتًا كثيرة
and road facilities,
وتجهيزات الطرق
you feel a sense of familiarity.
تحس بألفة كبيرة
Because
لأن
this is what home looks like.
هذا شكل الديرة
Then, arriving here, you find
ولما تجي هنا تلاحظ
the sky is very blue.
السماء زرقاء جدًا
If you drive just a bit outside the city,
إذا طلعت شوي بالسيارة خارج المدينة
there are vast stretches
بتشوف مساحات واسعة
of endless crops
محاصيل ما لها نهاية
and forests.
وغابات
Some are golden,
فيها الذهبي
some are green.
وفيها الأخضر
And with the sun shining on you,
والشمس تنسكب عليك
I feel that staying here,
أحس إنك لو تقعد بهالمكان
you don't really need to do anything specific.
ما تحتاج تسوي شيء مخصوص
You find a comfortable,
تلقى مكانًا مريحًا
favorite spot,
تحبه
and just sit there.
وتقعد هناك
You can sit quietly all afternoon,
وتجلس بهدوء طول العصر
and have no worries.
وما يبقى عندك همّ
It makes your body and mind happy.
ويصير جسمك ونفسك مرتاحين
I suggest everyone experience
أنصح الكل يجرّب
that Wetland Park.
منتزه الأراضي الرطبة
Go see the Red-crowned Cranes.
ويروح يشوف الكركي أحمر التاج
When that row of cranes
لما ذاك الصف من الكركي
flies over your head,
يطير فوق راسك
I'm telling you,
أقول لك
everyone might feel differently.
إحساس كل واحد ممكن يختلف
It's very moving.
مؤثر جدًا
But for me, it brought only awe and beauty.
بس أنا ما حسّيت إلا بالدهشة والجمال
Really.
صدقًا
Goosebumps.
قشعريرة
As the Northeast saying goes,
وبلهجتنا نقول المثل هذا
they just popped right up.
تطلع فجأة بلحظة
He said it all.
خلصنا الكلام
Nothing left to say, right?
ما عاد فيه شيء ينقال، صح؟
Indeed, nothing left to say.
فعلاً ما عاد فيه شيء ينقال
Everyone summarized it very well.
الجميع لخّصها بشكل شامل
And besides,
وبعدها
most of it is true.
أغلبه كان حقيقيًا
And some of it was
وفيه شوية
a bit embellished.
مبالغة وتجميل بسيط
I want to thank the production team.
شكرًا لفريق البرنامج
When we asked if we could
لما طرحنا سؤال: هل ممكن
come back to our hometown to film,
نرجع نصوّر مرة في ديرتنا
making such a request,
هذا الطلب
the team took it very seriously.
بس الفريق كان جادًا جدًا
It wasn't like
مو يعني
they just came because we asked.
أول ما قلناها جوا فورًا
They really brought a large crew
لا، جابوا طاقمًا كبيرًا فعلًا
many days in advance.
وجوا قبلها بأيام كثيرة
They truly found places worth filming.
وشافوا فعلًا أماكن تستاهل التصوير
And it really is beautiful.
وكمان جميلة جدًا
After watching it,
وأنتم لما تشوفونها
everyone will surely have
أكيد بيكون عندكم
this same feeling.
نفس هذا الإحساس
Most of all, I thank all the
وأكثر ناس أشكرهم هم أنتم
younger brothers and sisters.
يا إخواني الصغار وأخواتي الصغيرات
Thank you for bringing energy
شكرًا لأنكم لتشيتشيهار
to our Qiqihar.
جبتوا طاقة وحماس
Come on.
يلا
Cheers.
نخبكم
Thank you, everyone.
شكرًا لكم جميعًا
The setting sun beyond the Great Wall
شمس الأصيل في الشمال
is her red makeup.
هي حُمرتها
This is actually quite suitable for sleeping.
بصراحة هذا مكان مناسب للنوم
Quite suitable
ومناسب كمان
for staying right here.
إنك تقيم هنا
This is what you call
هذولا الناس أصلًا
proper camping.
يخيّمون بجدّ ومن دون مزح
The day we broke up,
يوم الفراق
I watched you walk away.
كنت أشوفك تبتعد
All promises turned into a full stop.
كل الوعود صارت نقطة نهاية
Roasted sweet potato.
بطاطا حلوة مشوية
Don't move.
لا تتحرك
It's hot, don't get burned.
حارّة، لا تحترق
There's some here.
هنا فيه
This is charcoal here, look.
هنا فحم، شوف
Yeah, just add a piece and it's done.
إيه، زوّدها شوي وخلاص
And the charcoal is still red.
وبعدين الفحم لسه محمّر
Don't get burned, be careful.
لا تحترق، انتبه
The orange is red.
البرتقال احمرّ
The departure group unlocks their first overseas trip
فريق الانطلاق يفتح أول رحلة خارجية
Welcome our flying guest
رحّبوا بضيفنا الطائر
I'm telling you
أقول لك
Every piece of clothing you picked for me
كل قطعة ملابس اخترتها لي
I am so dissatisfied with
أنا مو راضي عنها أبدًا
The color
اللون
The quality
الجودة
The taste
الذوق
I don't like any of them
كلها ما تعجبني
Your turn
دورك أنت
What "Old Money" style are you pretending to have?
إيش تمثّل ستايل الأثرياء القدامى، أنت؟
My Cantonese was completely led astray by him
لهجتي الكانتونية خربها عليّ تمامًا
Sorry
آسف
I went astray
أنا انحرفت
Hong Kong, China people speaking Hong Kong, China dialect
أهل هونغ كونغ في الصين يتكلمون لهجة هونغ كونغ
Is nothing special
وما هي إلا كذا
Grab
اسرع!
I can't do his moves
حركته ما أقدر أسويها.
You can
تقدر.
You are ten years younger than him
أنت أصغر منه بعشر سنين.
I can hardly imagine
حتى أنا مو قادر أتخيل.
Standing opposite Brother Weiting
أوقف قدّام أخ وي تينغ،
What the mood would be like
وش بيكون شعوري وقتها؟
Giving you this opportunity
أعطيك هالفرصة.
No
لا.
Compete one-on-one
نتحدّى بعض جولة لحالنا.
You want to
تبغى؟
Next time
المرة الجاية.
Come on
تعال.
Wang Anyu's competitor is here, I say
وانغ آنيو، المنافس وصل، أقول لك.
Hong Kong, China version "Great General"
نسخة هونغ كونغ من «الجنرال العظيم».
I want to give the title of "Great General Chen"
أبي أعطي لقب «الجنرال تشن»
To Brother Weiting
لأخ وي تينغ.
I can only say
ما أقدر أقول إلا...
If you two lose this round
إذا أنتم الاثنين خسرتوا هالجولة،
Darn it
انتهى الموضوع.
This is very clear
واضحة جدًا.
Midnight in Qiqihar
منتصف الليل في تشيتشيهار.
What
إيش؟
What am I doing
وش قاعد أسوي؟
Look if my drawing looks like you
شوف، رسمتك تشبهك ولا لا؟
So cute
مرّة كيوت.
Drawing Brother Teng doesn't require much
أخ Shen Teng ما يحتاج ترسمه كثير.
Draw a face, draw a nose
ارسم وجه، وارسم أنف،
Draw a mouth, draw six wrinkles and that's it
وفم، وست طيّات وخلاص.
Brother Teng these past two days
أخ Shen Teng هاليومين
Pure stimulation
كلها إثارة بس.
What are you doing
وش فيك؟
Pressed it before even drawing
لسه ما رسمت، وضغطت!
Can it be done like this
يصير كذا بعد؟
Tendons
وتر الرجل.
Da Xi
فرحة كبيرة!
You only got one question right all night
طول الليلة ما جاوبت صح إلا سؤال واحد.
During their time
ضمن وقتهم.
No
لا.
They beat us to it
خلّيتهم يسبقونا.
Let me see
خلّني أشوف.
Let me see Jingyu's
خلّني أشوف حق هوانغ جينغ يو.
Wang Anyu
وانغ آنيو.
Me
أنا.
Brother, your every...
يا أخي، كل مرة أنت...
I thought in those ten seconds down there
حسبتك في هالعشر ثواني تحت
What could you possibly draw
بتطلع لنا شي مفهوم.
After adding up your ten seconds
بس كل عشر ثوانيك إذا جمعناها،
It leaves us even more confused
تخلّينا أضيع أكثر.
How could a roller coaster appear here
كيف يطلع هنا... قطار أفعواني؟
These legs are
هذي الرجلين...
Too simple
سهل جدًا.
If we lose, we sleep wearing this
إذا خسرنا بننام وإحنا لابسين ذا.
This looks like he didn't train legs
واضح ما تمرّنت رجلينك.
Huang Jingyu
هوانغ جينغ يو.
Does he never train legs
صح إنك عمرك ما تمرّنت رجلينك؟
Never seen Sir Huang's legs
عمري ما شفت رجلين السيد هوانغ.
So it's like this
طلع كذا يعني.
Don't look
لا تطالع.
Don't look at my legs
لا تطالع رجولي.
Sitting in the office for a long time
قعدة مكتب لفترة طويلة.
You match this too well
هذا لايق عليك مرّة!
You look like
أنت كأنك...
You look like you came out wearing this
كأنك طالع من البيت وأنت لابس كذا.
These are my pants
هذي بنطلوني أصلًا.
All passengers please fasten your seatbelts
جميع الركّاب، رجاءً اربطوا أحزمة الأمان.
We are departing immediately
بننطلق حالًا.